<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press Archive - Pacific Serenades</title>
	<atom:link href="http://pacser.org/press/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://pacser.org/press/</link>
	<description>New chamber music from the west coast</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 04:39:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Pacific Serenades Premieres Sharon Farber&#8217;s &#8220;Bridges of Love&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://pacser.org/press/pacific-serenades-premieres-sharon-farbers-bridges-of-love/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Heather Henderson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 04:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pacser.org/?post_type=press&#038;p=282</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Pacific Serenades presents &#8220;Mixed Up World&#8221;, featuring the World Premiere of composer Sharon Farber&#8217;s &#8220;Bridges of Love&#8221;&#8230;plus works by Leonard ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/press/pacific-serenades-premieres-sharon-farbers-bridges-of-love/">Pacific Serenades Premieres Sharon Farber&#8217;s &#8220;Bridges of Love&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pacific Serenades presents &#8220;Mixed Up World&#8221;, featuring the World Premiere of composer Sharon Farber&#8217;s &#8220;Bridges of Love&#8221;&#8230;plus works by Leonard Bernstein, Gabriel Faure, and Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart</p>
<p>Featured musicians include tenor Shawn Thuris; Gary Gray, clarinet; Roland Kato, viola; and Robert Thies, piano</p>
<hr />
<p>Saturday, March 6; 8 p.m. at a private home in Tarzana<br />
Sunday, March 7; 4 p.m. at the Neighborhood Church in Pasadena<br />
Tuesday, March 9, at 8 p.m. at the UCLA Faculty Center in Westwood<br />
CALENDAR SUMMARY FOLLOWS RELEASE</p>
<hr />
<p>LOS ANGELES, Calif. When Mark Carlson, founder and Artistic Director of Pacific Serenades, asked composer Sharon Farber to write a new piece for the award-winning ensemble&#8217;s performances of &#8220;Mixed Up World&#8221; on March 6 at 8 p.m. at a private home in Tarzana, March 7 at 4 p.m. at the Neighborhood Church in Pasadena and Tuesday, March 9 at 8 p.m. at the UCLA Faculty Center in Los Angeles, the Israeli born composer didn&#8217;t hesitate to accept.</p>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;ve been a fan of this wonderful organization for a long time and attended their concerts, so I was delighted when Mark Carlson called,&#8221; recalls Farber, whose music was featured in a concert at Walt Disney Concert Hall last June, performed by The Jewish Symphony Orchestra and a 100-piece Gospel choir. &#8220;It&#8217;s an honor.&#8221;</p>
<p>The work that resulted from Carlson&#8217;s inquiry, Bridges of Love, sets three poems &#8211; one from the Book of Ruth, another by Helen Keller, and the last by the Sufi poet Rumi &#8211; to music. &#8220;I was looking for the right text for a long time,&#8221; Farber confesses. &#8220;I wanted to set music to poems about love, which I hadn&#8217;t done before but I couldn&#8217;t find poems that I could really relate to, as I was looking for non-romantic love. Then, a day before I started writing, I was given a book of love poems and, within a few minutes, I had found all three.</p>
<p>&#8220;The poems speak about uncommon, unconditional love,&#8221; Farber continues. &#8220;Love that is almost against all odds. They&#8217;re individual yet universal in their meaning. And I believe that love, as music, can bridge the gaps of faith and religion and can heal us all.&#8221;</p>
<p>Performing Bridges of Love are clarinetist Gary Gray, violist Roland Kato, pianist Robert Thies and tenor Shawn Thuris. &#8220;When Mark approached me, he asked that I write for this specific combination,&#8221; says Farber, whose list of past commissions includes writing for choirs like the Los Angeles Master Chorale and song cycles for sopranos. &#8220;I&#8217;ve written a lot for sopranos and loved the opportunity to write for a man&#8217;s voice, especially one as beautiful as Shawn&#8217;s. He is one of the best artists around, as well as the other wonderful musicians who&#8217;ll be part of this work.&#8221;</p>
<p>Thuris will also perform selected songs for tenor and piano by Gabriel Faure, with pianist Robert Thies as accompanist. &#8220;Robert and I chose the songs,&#8221; the tenor explains. &#8220;We are building the set around &#8216;En sourdine&#8217; and &#8216;Les matelots,&#8217; the former being a favorite of ours and the latter connecting to the theme of the concert. It depicts the globe-spanning &#8211; and idealized &#8211; life of a sailor. The differing musical styles provide a nice contrast as well.&#8221;</p>
<p>Rounding out &#8220;Mixed Up World&#8221; on the program are the Sonata for clarinet and piano by Leonard Bernstein and the Trio in E flat major, K. 498 for clarinet, viola and piano by Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart.</p>
<p>&#8220;This concert got as its title the theme of the whole season &#8211; Mixed Up World &#8211; because it seemed to encapsulate that idea even more so than the other programs,&#8221; says Carlson. &#8220;We have works by a 20th century American, a French composer who straddled the 19th and 20th centuries, an 18th century Austrian composer and an Israeli woman composer who has made her home in Los Angeles. &#8221;</p>
<p>The program, Carlson adds, follows a plan Pacific Serenades has followed since its founding 24 years ago: a work from the pre-20th century standard repertoire; something from the 20th century; and, as always, a brand new piece, commissioned by the ensemble.</p>
<p>&#8220;Composing is a lonely profession,&#8221; concludes Sharon Farber. &#8220;We sit in our studios all day and create something out of nothing. But nothing can compare to hearing your music played live &#8211; to hear it come to life after weeks or months of constant work.&#8221;</p>
<p>Tickets for &#8220;Mixed Up World&#8221; are available online, at www.pacser.org, or by calling 213.534.3434. Tickets for Private Home concerts and the post concert reception are $55/person; for the Neighborhood Church and UCLA Faculty Center, $32/person. (Neighborhood Church and UCLA Faculty Center tickets are also interchangeable.) Full time students with valid identification can purchase tickets &#8211; at the door only &#8211; at the Neighborhood Church or UCLA Faculty Center for $5.</p>
<p>The Neighborhood Church is located at 301 N. Orange Grove Blvd. in Pasadena. The Gamble House museum, next door to the church, offers a discounted tour at $8/person to Pacific Serenades patrons on concert dates only. Tours begin promptly at 2 pm and at 2:40 pm and last approximately one hour. Reservations are required and must be made at least 48 hours in advance of the concert date by calling 626.793.3334, ext. 16.</p>
<p>The UCLA Faculty Center is located at 405 N. Hilgard Ave. on the UCLA campus in Westwood. Parking is available for $10 in Lot 2. In addition, prior to each concert, dinner at the UCLA Faculty Center is available for Pacific Serenades patrons. Reservations can be made by calling 310.825.0877.</p>
<p>Directions and additional information about private home concerts are mailed to ticket holders upon receipt of their order.</p>
<p>The mission of Pacific Serenades is to generate new chamber music by commissioning works and presenting them alongside standard repertoire in intimate concert settings, emphasizing Southern California musicians. For more information about Pacific Serenades, its upcoming season, musicians and composers, visit www.pacser.org or call 213.534.3434. Subscriptions are currently available.</p>
<p>ABOUT COMPOSER SHARON FARBER<br />
Sharon Farber, originally from Israel, has received critical acclaim as a composer in the Concert world as well as that of Film and TV. She brings to her music influences from her Middle Eastern heritage as well as her extensive knowledge of Classical and Western music.</p>
<p>Sharon began her musical career at the age of seven, as a classical pianist. After graduating from Thelma -Yelin High School for the Arts, she served in the IDF (Israeli Defense Force) and later worked as a theater composer and musical director in Israel. She won the first prize in Colors in Dance in 1992 for her music for choreography. In 1994, she moved to Boston upon receiving a scholarship from Berklee College Of Music. During her studies, she won the first prize in the yearly Professional Writing Division Concert with her first string quartet. After graduating Summa Cum Laude in 1997 (majoring in both Classical Composition and Film Scoring) she moved to Los Angeles to begin her professional career. Miss Farber was the recipient of the prestigious Academy of Television Arts and Sciences Internship in Film Scoring, as well as the Mentorship program of the Society of Composers and Lyricists, on which she currently serves as a board member.</p>
<p>Ms. Farber, Composer In Residence of the 2009 Beverly Hills International Music Festival, has been writing concert and choir music in parallel to her film-scoring career, and has many international premieres and performances to her credit. To name a few: The Third Mother/Mothers&#8217; Lament, in memory of slain reporter Daniel Pearl, which was world premiered by the distinguished Los Angeles Master Chorale, under the direction of Maestro Grant Gershon, and won her the First Prize in the Cincinnati Camerata Composition Competition in 2007 (published by Roger Dean Music publishing), ASHKINA, featuring Omar Faruk Tekbilek, premiered in New York, October 2004, and has had many performances since. Her commissioned piece, Translucent Rocks, was premiered by the prestigious Israeli Chamber Orchestra, October 2007 to rave reviews. Her work &#8220;My Beloved&#8221; for Women&#8217;s Choir and Ensemble was premiered in April by The Ithaca College Women&#8217;s Chorale with Janet Galván, conductor and will be featured at the ACDA this coming February. Her song cycle, &#8220;To Always Remember&#8221; was recently recorded for an album by acclaimed Soprano Sharon Rostorf- Zamir. Ms. Farber&#8217;s music was featured in a concert at The Walt Disney Hall in Los Angeles June, 2009, performed by The Jewish Symphony Orchestra and a 100 piece Gospel choir. She has recently completed her Composer Residency at the 2009 Beverly Hills International Music Festival, where she curated two new concerts, and her film music has been featured time and again on &#8220;From Stage To Cinema&#8221; concert series. Her next commissions include the Laguna Beach Music festival and the prestigious MORAN choir from Israel.</p>
<p>In the Film and TV industry, Sharon has been working with such prestigious companies as NBC, CBS, Showtime and WB as well as writing music for features films and other projects. She won the Telly Award in 1998 for best score for the docu-drama series &#8220;California 2000&#8221; and her work can also be heard at the Museum of Sacramento, as part of the Museum&#8217;s permanent exhibition. Her orchestral score for &#8220;When Nietzsche Wept&#8221;, starring Aramand Assante and Ben cross (Millennium Films) was released October 20008, and she has recently completed the score for Folie a Deux for director Sean Martin (UK). In addition, she was commissioned to compose a new full CD for APM/SONOTON Music which is available on her website.</p>
<p>ABOUT THE MUSICIANS</p>
<p>Tenor Shawn Thuris<br />
Tenor Shawn Thuris brings a spectrum of vocal colors and experience in seven languages to his performances in recital, with orchestra, and on the operatic stage. Roles he has portrayed include Siegmund in Die Walküre, Radamès in Aïda, Mario in Tosca, Luigi in Il tabarro, and Hoffmann in Les Contes d&#8217;Hoffmann. He has sung at Orange County Performing Arts Center, Redlands Bowl Festival, UNLV, and the Bruno Walter Auditorium at Lincoln Center. Mr. Thuris has given many recitals of art song repertoire with pianists such as Kirill Gliadkovsky, Robert Thies, and Steven Vanhauwaert. He has been a soloist in oratorios of Bach, Handel, Lloyd Webber, and Mozart and has presented masterclasses at East Central University of Oklahoma. Mr. Thuris initially trained as a baritone with Marvin Hayes at Pomona College. He made the switch to tenor while studying with Gail Gordon at Santa Monica College, where he concluded his studies by performing a recital with orchestra in tribute to heldentenor Lauritz Melchior, with scenes from Die Meistersinger, Otello, Siegfried, and Tristan und Isolde. He has continued to refine his technique under the guidance of Dennis Parnell. In addition to these concerts with Pacific Serenades, highlights of the 2009-10 season include Bacchus in Ariadne auf Naxos with Brooklyn Repertory Opera, Don José in Carmen with New York Opera Forum, and a song recital at Pasadena City College. Mr. Thuris lives in New York with mezzo-soprano Monica Akemi Hershenson.</p>
<p>Gary Gray, Clarinet</p>
<p>Clarinetist Gary Gray enjoys a versatile career as a concert artist, studio musician, and professor of clarinet and chamber music at UCLA. He received his BM and MM degrees from Indiana University, where he studied clarinet with Henry Gulick and Robert McGinnis and chamber music with Janos Starker. The Los Angeles Times wrote of a recent concert, &#8220;Gray handled the clarinet solos with stunning ease and as mellow and gorgeous a sound as may be possible on his instrument.&#8221; Formerly Principal Clarinetist of LACO, comments such as &#8220;Gray astonished with his liquid clarinet solos&#8221; were frequent in the press. As a soloist, his concerto CD with the Royal Philharmonic Orchestra was nominated for a Grammy Award, and his CD of music for clarinet and piano, recorded in London with Clifford Benson, has also been a best seller for Centaur Records.</p>
<p>His most recent recording for Centaur Records includes two Romantic masterworks for clarinet and chamber ensemble: the Brahms Quintet Op. 115 and Dohnanyi&#8217;s Sextet Op. 37. For this project Gray collaborated with the New Hollywood Quartet, pianist, Robert Thies, and french hornist, Richard Todd.</p>
<p>Gray is a founding member/performer of Pacific Serenades and was a Faculty Artist at the Aspen Music Festival, Chamber Music Northwest, the Sedona Chamber Music Festival, and the Aria Music Academy. The summer of 2005, he joined the Alexander Quartet to perform and teach at the CSU Summer Arts chamber ensemble workshop. Gray has been a member of the St. Louis Symphony and performed with the Aspen Festival Orchestra, the Hollywood Bowl Orchestra, and has been soloist with the San Francisco Symphony, the Indianapolis Symphony, and LACO, among others.</p>
<p>He has collaborated with Aaron Copland, Malcolm Arnold, Benjamin Britten, Pierre Boulez, and Igor Stravinsky, as well as recording film scores with John Williams, Jerry Goldsmith, Henry Mancini, Thomas Newman, Bruce Broughton, and Don Davis, among many others.</p>
<p>Roland Kato, viola<br />
Described by the Los Angeles Times as &#8220;a brilliant virtuoso, playing with the perfect combination of energy and eloquence,&#8221; Roland Kato, internationally acclaimed viola recitalist and soloist, has been a member of LACO since 1976 and was appointed Principal Violist by Iona Brown in 1987. He has also held the principal position in many orchestras including the Music Center Opera Orchestra, the Pasadena Symphony, the California Chamber Symphony, and the Pasadena Chamber Orchestra. Mr. Kato plays chamber music with the Santa Clarita Chamber Players, Pacific Serenades, and other popular series in Los Angeles. As a guest artist, he recently was invited to play with the Chamber Music Society of Lincoln Center and has appeared with the New York New Music Ensemble. He was honored to perform chamber music with Yo-Yo Ma in a concert benefiting cancer research. In November 2002, he and LACO Concertmaster Margaret Batjer gave the West Coast premiere of Benjamin Britten&#8217;s double concerto in b minor for violin and viola.<br />
Mr. Kato has appeared as soloist/recitalist on both viola and viola d&#8217;amore throughout the US and abroad with LACO, Festival Casals in Puerto Rico, Grand Canyon Chamber Music Festival, Oregon Bach Festival, Festival Internacional de Musica (Costa Rica), among many other festivals.<br />
Mr. Kato produced the award-winning premiere recording of Telemann&#8217;s Quatrieme Livre de Quatours, a collection of six chamber pieces on the Koch Classics International label performed by the period instrument ensemble American Baroque. This recording has just been re-released on the Music and Arts label. He has also recorded chamber music of Tania French released on the Centaur label, and composer Mark Carlson&#8217;s Piano Quartet. The Carlson recording (The Hall of Mirrors) was awarded the Chamber Music America/WQXR Record Awards for 2001. Other chamber music recordings include those with Ransom Wilson and Marni Nixon.<br />
As a commissioned arranger of music Mr. Kato has had his pieces played worldwide. His transcription of Prokofiev&#8217;s Music for Children was recently given its New York premiere, and in Washington, D.C. his arrangement of Ravel&#8217;s Mother Goose Suite was premiered at the Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts by the New Hampshire-based Apple Hill Chamber Players. It was given its European premiere in Ireland and has consequently been performed throughout Europe and the US by various ensembles.</p>
<p>Robert Thies, piano</p>
<p>A pianist of &#8220;unerring, warm-toned refinement, revealing judicious glimmers of power,&#8221; [Los Angeles Times] Robert Edward Thies (pronounced &#8220;Theece&#8221;) is an artist renowned for his consummate musicianship and poetic temperament. He first captured worldwide attention in 1995 when he won the Gold Medal at the Second International Prokofiev Competition in St. Petersburg, Russia. With this victory, Thies became the only American pianist to win a Russian piano competition since Van Cliburn&#8217;s triumph in Moscow in 1958.</p>
<p>Thies enjoys a diverse career as an orchestral soloist, recitalist, and chamber musician. He has already performed over 35 concertos with orchestras all over the world, including the Saint Petersburg Philharmonic, the Auckland Philharmonia (New Zealand), the Mexico City Philharmonic, Mexico&#8217;s National Symphony, the Fort Worth Symphony, the Pasadena Symphony, the Louisville Orchestra, and the Naples Philharmonic.</p>
<p>Thies worked closely with Henryk Górecki in the U.S. premiere of his Sonata for Piano. In Mexico he performed Schoenberg&#8217;s Piano Concerto on the fiftieth anniversary of the composer&#8217;s death. He has performed at the music festivals of Ravinia, Aspen, Sedona, Breckenridge, Savannah Onstage, Cape May, and Music Academy of the West.</p>
<p>A dedicated chamber musician, Thies continues to expand an already impressive repertoire and collaborates with many esteemed musicians. He has appeared with established ensembles such as the Angeles, Calder, and New Hollywood String Quartets, and has also performed on the chamber series of Camerata Pacifica, Mladi, Dilijan and Jacaranda. He also founded The Thies Consort, a unique ensemble using varying instrumentation and thematic programming.</p>
<p>Born in 1971, Thies resides in Los Angeles. His teachers have included Robert Turner and Daniel Pollack, protégés of the legendary Russian pedagogue Madame Rosina Lhevinne. Mr. Thies is a Steinway artist. For more information, visit: www.robertthies.org.</p>
<p>ABOUT PACIFIC SERENADES<br />
The mission of Pacific Serenades is to generate new chamber music by commissioning works and presenting them alongside standard repertoire in intimate concert settings, emphasizing the talents of Southern California musicians.</p>
<p>Pacific Serenades has twice been awarded the prestigious Chamber Music America/ASCAP Award for Adventurous Programming, for our 2004-05 and 2002-03 seasons. The self-presenting ensemble has become one of the premier chamber music organizations in Southern California and one of the longest-performing on the West Coast since its first concert in 1982.</p>
<p>Now in its 24th full concert season, Pacific Serenades exists so that music lovers-listeners, performers, and composers alike-might experience chamber music as a living art-and to experience it in the intimate setting for which it is intended. The performers are among the best musicians of the Los Angeles area-indeed, of anywhere. Each of the four programs presents the premiere of a new work commissioned by Pacific Serenades along with standard repertoire, and each is performed in a private home, at the Neighborhood Church in Pasadena, and at the UCLA Faculty Center. By the end of its 24th season, Pacific Serenades will have presented the premieres of 98 new works-more than any other group of its kind in the country.</p>
<p>Representing 54 different composers, most of them from the Los Angeles area, many of these works have gone on to further performances by other ensembles throughout this country and in Europe and Canada, and many of them have already been published and recorded. The organization is beginning to publish its commissioned works in order to make them more available to other ensembles. Pacific Serenades gave its first New York concert, at Carnegie Recital Hall, in September of 1994, and its first San Francisco concert in January of 1998.</p>
<p>Pacific Serenades&#8217;s first CD, The Hall of Mirrors, was a winner of the 2001 Chamber Music America/WQXR Records Awards. Our newest CD, Border Crossings, features works we have premiered by Latin American-born composers (Miguel del Aguila and Enrique González-Medina) and other composers directly influenced by Latin American music (Robert Livingston Aldridge and Mark Carlson) was released in January 2008. A third, entitled War Scrap: that we may have peace, is in production and will include music by John Steinmetz, Larry Lipkis, and Mark Carlson.<br />
# # #</p>
<p>CALENDAR:<br />
PACIFIC SERENADES &#8211; &#8220;Mixed Up World&#8221;<br />
Sharon Farber: Bridges of Love<br />
Leonard Bernstein: Sonata for clarinet and piano<br />
Gabriel Faure: Selected Songs<br />
Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart: Trio in E flat major, K. 498<br />
Saturday, March 6; 8 p.m.; private home in Tarzana<br />
Sunday, March 7; 4 p.m.; Neighborhood Church<br />
301 N. Orange Grove Blvd. in Pasadena<br />
Tuesday, March 9; 8 p.m.; UCLA Faculty Center<br />
405 N. Hilgard Ave. on the UCLA campus<br />
Soloists:<br />
Shawn Thuris, tenor<br />
Gary Gray, clarinet<br />
Roland Kato, viola<br />
Robert Thies, piano<br />
Tickets: $32 (Neighborhood Church and UCLA Faculty Center)<br />
$55 (private home/reception)<br />
$5 for students with valid id at the door only (Neighborhood Church and UCLA)<br />
For more information, call 213.534.3434 or visit www.pacser.org.</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/press/pacific-serenades-premieres-sharon-farbers-bridges-of-love/">Pacific Serenades Premieres Sharon Farber&#8217;s &#8220;Bridges of Love&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pacific Serenades Opens Season With Work By Youngest Commissioned Composer</title>
		<link>http://pacser.org/press/pacific-serenades-opens-season-with-work-by-youngest-commissioned-composer/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Heather Henderson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2010 04:28:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pacser.org/?post_type=press&#038;p=280</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>PACIFIC SERENADES OPENS SEASON WITH NEW WORK BY YOUNGEST COMPOSER COMMISSIONED IN 24-YEAR HISTORY OF CHAMBER ENSEMBLE Program &#8211; entitled ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/press/pacific-serenades-opens-season-with-work-by-youngest-commissioned-composer/">Pacific Serenades Opens Season With Work By Youngest Commissioned Composer</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>PACIFIC SERENADES OPENS SEASON WITH NEW WORK BY YOUNGEST COMPOSER COMMISSIONED IN 24-YEAR HISTORY OF CHAMBER ENSEMBLE</p>
<p>Program &#8211; entitled &#8220;To Youth! To Wisdom!&#8221; &#8211; includes Quintessence by 25-year old composer Jeff Kryka, Brahms&#8217; String Quintet #1 in F Major and selected movements from Bartok&#8217;s 44 Duos for Two Violins</p>
<p>Violinists Tereza Stanislav and Brendan Speltz, violists Roland Kato and Connie Kupka and cellist David Speltz will perform</p>
<p>Saturday, January 30, 2010; 8 pm; at a private home in Culver City<br />
Sunday, January 31, 2010; 4 pm; The Neighborhood Church in Pasadena<br />
Tuesday, February 9, 2010; 8 pm; The UCLA Faculty Center<br />
Calendar Summary follows press release</p>
<p>LOS ANGELES, Calif. According to Mark Carlson, Artistic Director and Founder of Pacific Serenades, composers tend to develop more slowly &#8211; or later &#8211; than performers. &#8220;It&#8217;s unusual to hear music by someone who already has his own voice at age 25 and who also has the compositional skill to express that voice,&#8221; says Carlson, a flutist who has composed nearly 100 works and whose recording of his works, The Hall of Mirrors, was a winner of the Chamber Music America/WQXR Record Awards for 2001.</p>
<p>But there are exceptions to every rule, as audiences will discover when they hear the World Premiere of Quintessence by composer Jeff Kryka, 25, on Saturday, January 30 at 8 p.m. at a private home in Culver City; Sunday, January 31 at 4 p.m. at the Neighborhood Church in Pasadena; and Tuesday, February 9 at 8 p.m. at the UCLA Faculty Center in Los Angeles. &#8220;Jeff definitely has his own unique voice, which is what caught my attention about him,&#8221; says Carlson of the young composer, a First Prize winner of the Turner Classic Movies Young Film Composers Competition in 2006.</p>
<p>Also on the program, entitled &#8220;To Youth! To Wisdom!,&#8221; are String Quintet #1 in F Major by Johannes Brahms and Bela Bartok&#8217;s 44 Duos for Two Violins.</p>
<p>&#8220;This season, our 24th, there is a little subtheme running through all but the 3rd concert,&#8221; Carlson explains. &#8220;We&#8217;re programming new compositions from 2010, then coupling them with a work from the first half of the 20th century and an older piece. 44 Duos for Two Violins, written in 1931, obviously fits into that equation. The duos are just amazing, beautiful gems. Some of them are only 30 seconds long and none is longer than a couple of minutes or so. They are flashy, fun, poignant, and colorful. They show off the violins beautifully, violinists love playing them, and audiences always find them captivating.&#8221;</p>
<p>When asked about Brahms&#8217; inclusion in &#8220;To Youth! To Wisdom!,&#8221; Carlson smiles. &#8220;Brahms&#8217;s music always sounds as if written by a wise old man. Also, it&#8217;s full of the typically rich sonorities and beautiful, singing melodies that we associate with Brahms.&#8221;</p>
<p>As for the youngest composer, Jeff Kryka, almost as much thought went into christening his new work as writing it. For starters, Quintessence reflects the dictionary definition of the term: the pure, concentrated essence of a thing or the perfect embodiment of it. But the explanation for the title of the 5-movement work goes far beyond that.</p>
<p>&#8220;Quintessence, literally the &#8216;fifth essence,&#8217; was thought by the ancients to be the purest, most rarefied element &#8211; after earth, air, fire, and water &#8211; of which the planets, sun, moon, and stars were made,&#8221; Kryka explains. &#8220;Plato theorized about its existence in Timaeus, a dialogue which is also notable for his discussions of music, the Pythagorean scale, and the Doctrine of Ethos-the influence of music on human emotion and morality.&#8221;</p>
<p>Contemporary astrophysicists have also borrowed the term, Kryka continues, to describe a hypothetical form of Dark Energy-a force that, along with Dark Matter, permeates all of space. Currently the most prevalent theory among scientists to explain the accelerated expansion of the universe, Quintessence is thought to account for three-quarters of the total mass-energy of the universe.</p>
<p>&#8220;Naturally, I found the concept of Quintessence instantly appealing for the basis of a string quintet,&#8221; says Kryka. &#8221; I always imagined the motion of celestial bodies to be something like a dance. Watching the way the planets wandered across the sky, sometimes retrograde to the movement of the moon, sun, and stars, I like to think this is how the ancients saw the universe too. By the end of the fifth movement, with the 5-note motive transformed into a great chorale, this is what Quintessence has become: the music of the spheres.&#8221;</p>
<p>Last but not least, Quintessence is written for a quintet &#8211; for two violins, two violas and cello. Musicians taking part in &#8220;To Youth! To Wisdom!&#8221; include violinists Tereza Stanislav, assistant concertmaster of the Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra, and Brendan Speltz; violists Roland Kato and Connie Kupka; and cellist David Speltz.</p>
<p>&#8220;Brendan is the son of long time Pacific Serenades members Connie Kupka and David Speltz,&#8221; says Carlson. &#8220;Since our founding in 1982, we&#8217;ve always said that, at Pacific Serenades, we&#8217;re a family. And this concert proves this in a whole new way!&#8221;</p>
<p>Tickets for &#8220;To Youth! To Wisdom!&#8221; are available online, at www.pacser.org, or by calling 213.534.3434. Tickets for Private Home concerts and the post concert reception are $55/person; for the Neighborhood Church and UCLA Faculty Center, $32/person. (Neighborhood Church and UCLA Faculty Center tickets are also interchangeable.) Full time students with valid identification can purchase tickets &#8211; at the door only &#8211; at the Neighborhood Church or UCLA Faculty Center for $5.</p>
<p>The Neighborhood Church is located at 301 N. Orange Grove Blvd. in Pasadena. The Gamble House museum, next door to the church, offers a discounted tour at $8/person to Pacific Serenades patrons on concert dates only. Tours begin promptly at 2 pm and at 2:40 pm and last approximately one hour. Reservations are required and must be made at least 48 hours in advance of the concert date by calling 626.793.3334, ext. 16.</p>
<p>The UCLA Faculty Center is located at 405 N. Hilgard Ave. on the UCLA campus in Westwood. Parking is available for $10 in Lot 2. In addition, prior to each concert, dinner at the UCLA Faculty Center is available for Pacific Serenades patrons. Reservations can be made by calling 310.825.0877.</p>
<p>Directions and additional information about private home concerts are mailed to ticket holders upon receipt of their order.</p>
<p>The mission of Pacific Serenades is to generate new chamber music by commissioning works and presenting them alongside standard repertoire in intimate concert settings, emphasizing Southern California musicians. For more information about Pacific Serenades, its upcoming season, musicians and composers, visit www.pacser.org or call 213.534.3434. Subscriptions are currently available.</p>
<p>ABOUT COMPOSER JEFF KRYKA</p>
<p>Although only 25 years old, composer Jeff Kryka has already received awards from Turner Classic Movies, ASCAP, the RMA L.A., the Henry Mancini Foundation and has had works performed in concert by virtuoso violinist Anne Akiko Meyers, the University of Wisconsin-Madison Symphony Orchestra, the University of Wisconsin-Madison Concert Band, and the Heartland Symphony Orchestra.</p>
<p>In addition, Kryka has served as composer for many films, most notably: Las Angeles (dir. Gerardo Flores Villarreal, Maverick Productions), Deserted (dir. Nils Timm, AFI), Forgive Us Our Transgressions, (dir Walter Richardson, UCLA), Cherchez La Femme (dir. Idit Dvir, Gaia Films), Code Duello (dir. Nora Gruber, UCLA), The End (dir. Maggie Ye, UCLA), and Changing Focus (dir. Mindy Ramaker, UW-Madison)</p>
<p>In 2008, as a participant in the ASCAP Film and Television Scoring Workshop, Kryka conducted his music with the Hollywood Studio Symphony at 20th Century Fox&#8217;s Newman Scoring Stage. During the summer of 2007, he taught a UCLA course in film music with Paul Chihara and music editor Dan Carlin and in the fall of that year interned in the television music department at 20th Century Fox Studios under Carol Farhat, where he oversaw recording sessions for hit TV shows such as the Simpsons, Family Guy, and American Dad. In 2006, Kryka was named the First Prize winner of the Turner Classic Movies Young Film Composers Competition. His score was chosen out of a field of over 650 international participants and judged by Academy Award-winning composer Hans Zimmer.</p>
<p>Kryka studied music composition at the University of Wisconsin-Madison with composers Stephen Dembski and Laura Schwendinger, receiving his undergraduate degree in May 2006. In the fall of that year he began graduate work at the University of California-Los Angeles, studying with composers Paul Chihara, Roger Bourland, Ian Krouse, and David Lefkowitz. At UCLA, he also studies film music with composers Charles Fox and Laura Karpman, as well as orchestration with Bruce Broughton. He has been a teaching assistant for composers Russell Steinberg and Mark Carlson, and he teaches music theory and musicianship to undergraduate music majors.</p>
<p>ABOUT THE MUSICIANS (alphabetical)</p>
<p>Described by the Los Angeles Times as &#8220;a brilliant virtuoso, playing with the perfect combination of energy and eloquence,&#8221; Roland Kato, internationally acclaimed viola recitalist and soloist, has been a member of LACO since 1976 and was appointed Principal Violist by Iona Brown in 1987. He has also held the principal position in many orchestras including the Music Center Opera Orchestra, the Pasadena Symphony, the California Chamber Symphony, and the Pasadena Chamber Orchestra. Kato also plays chamber music with the Santa Clarita Chamber Players, Pacific Serenades and other popular ensembles in Los Angeles.</p>
<p>As a guest artist, Kato recently was invited to play with the Chamber Music Society of Lincoln Center and has appeared with the New York New Music Ensemble. He was also honored to perform chamber music with Yo-Yo Ma in a concert benefiting cancer research. In November 2002, he and LACO Concertmaster Margaret Batjer gave the West Coast premiere of Benjamin Britten&#8217;s double concerto in b minor for violin and viola.</p>
<p>Kato has appeared as soloist/recitalist on both viola and viola d&#8217;amore throughout the US and abroad with LACO, Festival Casals in Puerto Rico, Grand Canyon Chamber Music Festival, Oregon Bach Festival, Festival Internacional de Musica (Costa Rica), among many other festivals. In addition, he produced the award-winning premiere recording of Telemann&#8217;s Quatrieme Livre de Quatours, a collection of six chamber pieces on the Koch Classics International label performed by the period instrument ensemble American Baroque. This recording has just been re-released on the Music and Arts label. He has also recorded chamber music of Tania French released on the Centaur label, and composer Mark Carlson&#8217;s Piano Quartet. The Carlson recording (The Hall of Mirrors) was awarded the Chamber Music America/WQXR Record Awards for 2001. Other chamber music recordings include those with Ransom Wilson and Marni Nixon.</p>
<p>As a commissioned arranger of music, Kato&#8217;s works have been performed worldwide. His transcription of Prokofiev&#8217;s Music for Children was recently given its New York premiere, and in Washington, D.C. his arrangement of Ravel&#8217;s Mother Goose Suite was premiered at the Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts by the New Hampshire-based Apple Hill Chamber Players. It received its European premiere in Ireland and has consequently been performed throughout Europe and the US by various ensembles.</p>
<p>Connie Kupka, violist and violinist, was born and raised in Los Angeles where she studied at UCLA and began her professional career. In 1972, she won a scholarship to study chamber music with the Guarneri Quartet and concurrently worked with the violin pedagogue, Broadus Earle. In 1973, Kupka joined the Arriaga Quartet, which won First Prize in the Coleman competition in Pasadena. The following year, she debuted at Town Hall in New York with the ensemble.</p>
<p>Kupka has participated in many summer chamber music festivals, including those in Santa Fe, the Grand Canyon, the Oregon Bach Festival, the Mainly Mozart Festival in San Diego, and the Ojai Music Festival. She has served as Principal Violinist for LACO, the Pasadena Symphony, and the Colorado Music Festival and has appeared as soloist with the South Bay Symphony and Colorado Chamber Orchestra.</p>
<p>A member of LACO for 14 seasons, Kupka augments her Los Angeles orchestral activities with chamber music performances for such series as the South Bay Chamber Music series and Monday Evening Concerts. She is also active in motion picture studio orchestras.</p>
<p>Violinist Brendan Speltz is currently a student at the USC Thornton School of Music, working with Margaret Batjer. During the past several summers, Speltz has studied chamber music extensively with the Colorado Quartet at Soundfest, Cape Cod with Marion Feldman, at the NYU Quartet workshop in New York City, at the Bowdoin Music Festival in Maine and the International Academy of Music in St. Petersburg, Russia and Niagara Falls, Canada. He has also participated in such established professional chamber music series as the South Bay Chamber Music Society and Pacific Serenades and has performed several times on the broadcasts from the Los Angeles County Museum of Arts on KMZT. The young violinist has also performed in orchestras under the direction of Larry Livingston at the Idyllwild School of Music and was selected to play under Helmuth Rilling at the Bach Academy in Stuttgart.</p>
<p>David Speltz, cellist, began his formal studies with Eleanore Schoenfeld after being introduced to the cello by his father. Later, he was invited to join the Piatigorsky masterclass at USC.</p>
<p>He earned a master&#8217;s degree in mathematics from UCLA but soon realized that music was the path he should follow. In 1973, he helped form the Arriaga String Quartet, which went on to win first prize in the prestigious Coleman competition in Pasadena.</p>
<p>As a member of the Musical Offering ensemble, Speltz has performed at the Library of Congress, Lincoln Center, Casals Festival in Puerto Rico, and recorded on the Nonesuch label. He has also participated in many of the chamber music series in Los Angeles, including Pacific Serenades, Chamber Music in Historic Sites, the Bing series, the IMA, South Bay, and LACMA chamber music series. During the summer months, he participates in music festivals in Santa Fe, the Grand Canyon, and at the Oregon Bach Festival.</p>
<p>Speltz was a member of LACO during Sir Neville Marriner&#8217;s tenure and principal cellist of the California Chamber Symphony for eight seasons. In 1989, he was invited by Helmuth Rilling to serve as principal cellist of the Bachakademie in Stuttgart, Germany. He is also active in the Los Angeles recording field, performing on such films as Schindler&#8217;s List and Jurassic Park.</p>
<p>Violinist Tereza Stanislav was appointed Assistant Concertmaster of the Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra in 2003 by Artistic Director Jeffrey Kahane. Dividing her time among solo, orchestral, chamber and recording projects, Stanislav has been hailed for her &#8220;expressive beauty and wonderful intensity&#8221; (Robert Mann) and her &#8220;sure technique and musical intelligence&#8221; (Calgary Herald).</p>
<p>An active performer, Stanislav has appeared in venues including the Library of Congress, the Kennedy Center, Wigmore Hall, the Ravinia Music Festival and at Carnegie Hall&#8217;s Weill Recital Hall. She has performed in concert with artists including Jean-Yves Thibaudet, Gilbert Kalish, Jon Kimura Parker, Jian Wang and Mark Steinberg. In 2004, Tereza released a CD in collaboration with pianist Hung-Kuan Chen.</p>
<p>In 2009, Stanislav was invited to be the Chamber Music Collaborator for Sonata Programs for the Sixth Esther Honens International Piano Competition, as well as the soloist on a Central European tour performing Mozart&#8217;s Fifth Violin Concerto. In addition, she was invited to join the Miró Quartet for their summer program, including performances at Chamber Music Northwest, Santa Fe Music Festival and La Jolla Summerfest.</p>
<p>As a founding member of the Ens? String Quartet, Stanislav was awarded the Second Prize of the 2004 Banff International String Quartet Competition, and led the quartet to win the Special Prize awarded for best performance of the &#8220;Piece de Concert&#8221;, commissioned for the competition. The quartet was a winner of the 2003 Concert Artists Guild, Chamber Music Yellow Springs and Fischoff competitions. The Strad magazine cited the quartet for &#8220;&#8230;totally committed, imaginative interpretation that emphasized contrasts of mood, dynamics and articulation.&#8221;</p>
<p>With the Ens?, Stanislav is featured on the Naxos recording of the complete Ignaz Pleyel quartets, Op.2. The quartet was highlighted on the Minnesota Public Radio&#8217;s &#8220;St. Paul Sunday&#8221; in 2004, and was appointed to a Lectureship in String Quartet at Rice University&#8217;s Shepherd School of Music in the 2004-2005 academic year.</p>
<p>An advocate for new music, Stanislav has worked with composers including Steve Reich, Joan Tower, Toshio Hosokawa and Karim Al-Zand. Premieres include James Matheson&#8217;s Violin Sonata, Bruce Adolphe&#8217;s Oceanophony, the 2009 world premiere of Gernot Wolfgang&#8217;s Rolling Hills and Jagged Ridges and the West Coast premieres of Steve Reich&#8217;s Daniel Variations and Gernot Wolfgang&#8217;s Jazz and Cocktails. She is featured on a new recording of the Wolfgang on Albany Records and the Reich on Nonesuch label.</p>
<p>She is active in the film scoring industry in Los Angeles and in 2009, co-created the new music series, In Frequency.</p>
<p>ABOUT PACIFIC SERENADES</p>
<p>Founded in 1982, Pacific Serenades is one of the longest performing ensembles on the west coast, featuring many of the most acclaimed musicians in Southern California -including principals from the Los Angeles Philharmonic, Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra, The Pasadena Symphony and the Long Beach Symphony. Yet, while most chamber ensembles offer either all-new music or all-traditional repertoire, Pacific Serenades makes a point of including both at each concert.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s very important for people to hear-and play-a new piece in the context of masterpieces of the past,&#8221; says founder Mark Carlson. &#8220;I really want new music to be heard as part of an ongoing tradition, rather than as a new art form with no roots.&#8221;</p>
<p>By June 2010, Pacific Serenades will have commissioned and premiered 98 new works by 54 different composers, with many of these works receiving as many as 50-60 additional performances worldwide following their premieres. Carlson, himself, is the recipient of more than 40 commissions and has composed works for the National Shrine in Washington, DC and the New West Symphony, among others, as well as many individual musicians.</p>
<p>Concerts currently take place at three venues, each selected to replicate the smaller, more intimate environment in which chamber music historically was performed: the Neighborhood Church in Pasadena; the UCLA Faculty Center; and a private home in Los Angeles. In addition, Pacific Serenades gave its first New York concert, at Carnegie Recital Hall, in September of 1994, and its first San Francisco concert in January of 1998.</p>
<p>Recently, Pacific Serenades won its second Adventurous Programming Award from ASCAP and Chamber Music America, in addition to a CMA/WQXR Record Award, in 2001, for its first CD, Mark Carlson&#8217;s The Hall of Mirrors. The ensemble&#8217;s latest CD, Border Crossings &#8211; featuring new works by Enrique Gonzalez-Medina, Robert Livingston Aldridge, Mark Carlson, and Miguel del Aguila &#8211; illustrates how the composers &#8211; two, Latin American-born and two, overtly influenced by Latin American music &#8211; have artistically crossed the border between the United States and Latin America.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Latin-born composers brought those influences with them when they moved here, and the others of us actively went to Latin America, seeking them,&#8221; explains Carlson.</p>
<p>A third CD, entitled &#8220;War Scrap: that we may have peace&#8221;, will include music by John Steinmetz, Larry Lipkis, and Mark Carlson. CDs may be purchased through Pacific Serenades&#8217; website, www.pacser.org or by calling 213.534.3434.</p>
<p># # #</p>
<p>CALENDAR:<br />
PACIFIC SERENADES &#8211; &#8220;To Youth! To Wisdom!&#8221;<br />
Jeff Kryka: Quintessence<br />
Brahms: String Quintet #1 in F Major<br />
Bartok: selected movements from 44 Duos for Two Violins<br />
Saturday, January 30; 8 p.m.; private home in Brentwood<br />
Sunday, January 31; 4 p.m.; Neighborhood Church<br />
301 N. Orange Grove Blvd. in Pasadena<br />
Tuesday, February 9; 8 p.m.; UCLA Faculty Center<br />
405 N. Hilgard Ave. on the UCLA campus<br />
Soloists:<br />
Tereza Stanislav, violin<br />
Brendan Speltz, violin<br />
Roland Kato, viola<br />
Connie Kupka, viola<br />
David Speltz, cello<br />
Tickets: $32 (Neighborhood Church and UCLA Faculty Center)<br />
$55 (private home/reception)<br />
$5 for students with valid id at the door only (Neighborhood Church and UCLA)<br />
For more information, call 213.534.3434 or visit www.pacser.org</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/press/pacific-serenades-opens-season-with-work-by-youngest-commissioned-composer/">Pacific Serenades Opens Season With Work By Youngest Commissioned Composer</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pacific Serenades Presents World Premiere of Mark Carlson&#8217;s View from a Hilltop</title>
		<link>http://pacser.org/press/pacific-serenades-presents-world-premiere-of-mark-carlsons-view-from-a-hilltop/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Heather Henderson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2009 04:23:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pacser.org/?post_type=press&#038;p=278</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Pacific Serenades to present world premiere of composer Mark Carlson&#8217;s new work for clarinet, violin, cello and piano &#8211; View ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/press/pacific-serenades-presents-world-premiere-of-mark-carlsons-view-from-a-hilltop/">Pacific Serenades Presents World Premiere of Mark Carlson&#8217;s View from a Hilltop</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pacific Serenades to present world premiere of composer Mark Carlson&#8217;s new work for clarinet, violin, cello and piano &#8211; View from a Hilltop &#8211; written for his friends in honor of his aunt.<br />
Performing at &#8220;Music Among Friends&#8221; are Carlson&#8217;s longtime colleagues clarinetist Gary Gray, violinist Roger Wilkie, cellist David Speltz and pianist Joanne Pearce Martin</p>
<p>Saturday, March 21, 2009; 8 pm; at a private home in Tarzana<br />
Sunday, March 22, 2009; 4 pm; The Neighborhood Church in Pasadena<br />
Tuesday, March 24, 2009; 8 pm; The UCLA Faculty Center<br />
Calendar Summary follows press release</p>
<hr size="1" />
<p>LOS ANGELES, Calif. By his own admission, composer Mark Carlson is often the first to leave a party &#8211; or to skip it altogether &#8211; so he can get back to work on his latest commission. Music lovers throughout Southern California will have a chance to hear Carlson&#8217;s most recent composition when the award winning chamber ensemble, Pacific Serenades, presents the World Premiere of Carlson&#8217;s View from a Hilltop for clarinet/bass clarinet, violin, cello and piano on Saturday, March 21 at 8 p.m. at a private home in Tarzana; Sunday, March 22 at 4 p.m. at The Neighborhood Church in Pasadena; and Tuesday, March 24 at 8 p.m. at the UCLA Faculty Center.</p>
<p>Also on the program &#8211; entitled &#8220;Music Among Friends&#8221; &#8211; are Brahms&#8217; Clarinet Trio in A minor, Op. 114 and Ravel&#8217;s Sonata for Violin and Piano. Clarinetist Gary Gray, violinist Roger Wilkie, cellist David Speltz and pianist Joanne Pearce Martin will perform.</p>
<p>&#8220;The title, View from a Hilltop, just jumped into my mind,&#8221; recalls Carlson, who wrote the work after his extended family of cousins and aunts and uncles &#8211; owners of Leavens Ranches in Ventura County &#8211; commissioned View from a Hilltop in honor of his 81 year old aunt, Dr. Dorothy Leavens Carlson, who grew up in Ventura. &#8220;A person in old age has a kind of perspective on life that is similar to sitting on a hilltop, being able to see down below, as well as whatever is above.&#8221;</p>
<p>Carlson readily confesses to a preference for instrumentations that combine winds, strings and piano. &#8220;It&#8217;s an instrumentation that Olivier Messiaen started with his Quartet for the End of Time, which he composed while he was a prisoner of war from June 1940 to March 1941. The clarinet, violin, cello and piano were the only instruments available to him,&#8221; Carlson explains.</p>
<p>View from a Hilltop is Carlson&#8217;s third piece written for this type of quartet. But although Carlson claims that he is always inspired by &#8220;the sheer fun of writing for that type of quartet,&#8221; the creative process was not without its challenges. &#8220;I couldn&#8217;t figure out this piece-I struggled with it more than I usually do,&#8221; the composer admits. &#8220;It was very frustrating, and I think part of it was because I was trying so hard for it to be-not really classical-but I thought it was going to be three big movements. But it just hasn&#8217;t turned out that way.&#8221;</p>
<p>The completed work is five movements. &#8220;There is something to the idea that a piece, at some point, starts asserting itself, what it wants to be,&#8221; says Carlson, who teaches music theory and composition at UCLA. &#8220;Talking so much about the nuts and bolts of music and analyzing one great piece after another in class, year after year, gives me such reverence for the loving care, the amazing attention to detail, that composers take in their work. Those works are definitely inspired, but they don&#8217;t turn out so beautifully by accident, either. And I want nothing less for my own music.&#8221;</p>
<p>Nor is it an accident that View from a Hilltop will make its debut in the company of works by icons like Brahms and Ravel. &#8220;This allows the audience to realize what should be obvious,&#8221; explains Carlson, a professional flutist who founded Pacific Serenades in 1982. &#8220;Every composer in the past was a composer of new music, yet because of their god-like stature in our present mentality, we forget that they were cranking out new music all of the time.&#8221;</p>
<p>Carlson chose the title &#8220;Music among friends&#8221; because all four of the musicians performing have been involved with Pacific Serenades long enough for him to view them as friends. Gray has performed with the ensemble since 1987; Wilkie, since 1988; Speltz, since 1989. Even Pearce Martin, a relative newcomer, has been on board for 15 years, since 1993.</p>
<p>&#8220;I write for them with an intimacy that I wouldn&#8217;t have writing for players I don&#8217;t know well,&#8221; Carlson explains. &#8220;I have written various pieces for each of them &#8211; and often enough that I feel really comfortable writing for them. Plus they always seem eager to play whatever I come up with. I don&#8217;t feel like I have to write in a specific style to make them happy.&#8221;</p>
<p>The recipient of more than 40 commissions, Carlson has composed works for organizations nationwide, ranging from the National Shrine in Washington, DC and the Boston Gay Men&#8217;s Chorus to the New West Symphony, Westwood Presbyterian Church, First Methodist Church of Santa Monica, the UCLA Wind Ensemble, and the Santa Monica College Orchestra in Southern California. He has also received commissions from such artists as Canadian trumpeter Jens Lindemann and pianist Jennifer Snow.</p>
<p>Recent commissions include Sueños y canciones for the Mexico City chamber ensemble, Signos, and From the Song of Songs, a work for soprano and piano recorded by soprano Diana Guhin Wooley and pianist Richard Steinbach of the American Celebration Duo. Publishers of Carlson&#8217;s music include Yelton Rhodes Music, Pacific Serenades Music, and C Swigart Music in Los Angeles; Thorpe Music in Boston; and Black Squirrel Music, in Kent, Ohio.</p>
<p>In 2001, &#8220;The Hall of Mirrors&#8221; &#8211; one of eleven recordings of Carlson&#8217;s works &#8211; won a Chamber Music America/WQXR Record Award. At least two additional CDs are scheduled for release as well in 2009.</p>
<p>In addition to founding Pacific Serenades, Carlson was a member of The Pasadena Symphony, the YMF Debut Orchestra, and the Fresno Philharmonic Orchestra, among others. Currently on the faculty at UCLA, Carlson also taught at Santa Monica College from 1993 to 2008. Since 1982 he has served on the Board of Directors of Design for Sharing, UCLA&#8217;s Performing Arts community outreach program.</p>
<p>Tickets for the March 21 concert and post concert reception at a private home are available for $55/person. Tickets for performances at The Neighborhood Church in Pasadena and the UCLA Faculty Center are $32/person. Full time student tickets are available at the door only, at Neighborhood Church and UCLA, for $5. To purchase tickets or learn more about season subscriptions, visit www.pacser.org or call 213.534.3434.</p>
<p>The Neighborhood Church is located at 301 N. Orange Grove Blvd. in Pasadena. The Gamble House museum, next door to the church, offers a discounted tour at $8/person to Pacific Serenades patrons on concert dates only. Tours begin promptly at 2 pm and at 2:40 pm and last approximately one hour. Reservations are required and must be made at least 48 hours in advance of the concert date by calling 626.793.3334, ext. 16.</p>
<p>The UCLA Faculty Center is located at 405 N. Hilgard Ave. on the UCLA campus in Westwood. Parking is available for $9 in Lot 2. In addition, prior to each concert, dinner at the UCLA Faculty Center is available for Pacific Serenades patrons. Reservations can be made by calling 310.825.0877.</p>
<p>Directions and additional information about private home concerts are mailed to ticket holders upon receipt of their order.</p>
<p>The mission of Pacific Serenades is to generate new chamber music by commissioning works and presenting them alongside standard repertoire in intimate concert settings, emphasizing Southern California musicians. For more information about Pacific Serenades, its upcoming season, musicians and composers, visit www.pacser.org or call 213.534.3434.</p>
<p>ABOUT THE MUSICIANS</p>
<p>Gary Gray, clarinet<br />
Over the course of his career, Gary Gray, a founding member of Pacific Serenades and Principal Clarinetist for the Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra, has collaborated with such legendary composers as Aaron Copland, Malcolm Arnold, Benjamin Britten, Pierre Boulez and Igor Stravinsky as well as with John Williams, Jerry Goldsmith, Henry Mancini, Thomas Newman, Bruce Broughton, and Don Davis from the film industry. Gray has also performed with the St. Louis Symphony, the Aspen Festival Orchestra, and the Hollywood Bowl Orchestra and appeared as a soloist with the San Francisco Symphony, the Indianapolis Symphony, and LACO, among others.</p>
<p>&#8220;Gray handled the clarinet solos with stunning ease and as mellow and gorgeous a sound as may be possible on his instrument,&#8221; wrote the Los Angeles Times after a recent performance.</p>
<p>In addition, Gray&#8217;s album of solo concerti, recorded with the Royal Philharmonic Orchestra was nominated for a Grammy Award in the category of Best Soloist with Orchestra &#8211; the second time in Grammy history that a clarinet album received such a nomination. For his most recent recording for Centaur Records with the Hollywood Quartet, Gray collaborated with pianist Robert Thies, and Richard Todd on French Horn.</p>
<p>&#8220;Gary Gray&#8230; sounds to me about as close to Reginald Kell (another iconoclast) as I have ever heard,&#8221; wrote Steve Ritter of the American Record Guide. &#8220;Something this bunch is doing&#8230;.and I am almost at a loss to tell you exactly what it is&#8230;.gets right to the heart of this music.&#8221;</p>
<p>Roger Wilkie, violin<br />
Violinist Roger Wilkie&#8217;s violin playing has been described as &#8220;having surpassing virtuosity, a thrilling legato tone, and a sense of full emotional engagement&#8221; by the LA Times. Currently the concertmaster of the Long Beach Symphony, Wilkie has also served in that capacity with the Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra, the Los Angeles Music Center Opera Orchestra, and the Real Filharmonia de Galicia in Spain and was the Principal Violinist of the Camerata Pacifica of Santa Barbara.</p>
<p>Wilkie has also appeared as soloist with numerous orchestras including the Long Beach Symphony, the Santa Barbara Chamber Orchestra, LACO, and the Carmel Bach Festival Orchestra. An extremely active chamber musician, Wilkie has participated in the Santa Fe, La Jolla, and Mainly Mozart festivals and has given solo recitals for the San Luis Obispo Mozart Festival, LACMA/KUSC-FM, NPR&#8217;s Performance Today, and Swiss National Radio.</p>
<p>David Speltz, cello<br />
Cellist David Speltz, earned a master&#8217;s degree in mathematics from UCLA but soon realized that his heart &#8211; and career &#8211; lay in music. A member of the Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra during Sir Neville Marriner&#8217;s tenure and principal cellist of the California Chamber Symphony for eight seasons, Speltz has participated in chamber music series throughout Los Angeles, including Pacific Serenades, Chamber Music in Historic Sites, the Bing series, and the IMA, South Bay, and LACMA chamber music series. In addition, during the summer months, the cellist participates in music festivals in Santa Fe, the Grand Canyon, and Oregon. As a member of the Musical Offering ensemble, the cellist has performed at the Library of Congress and Lincoln Center in Washington D.C., the Casals Festival in Puerto Rico, and recorded on the Nonesuch label. In 1989, Speltz was invited by Helmuth Rilling to serve as principal cellist of the Bachakademie in Stuttgart, Germany.</p>
<p>Joanne Pearce Martin, piano<br />
Currently enjoying her 8th season as the Los Angeles Philharmonic&#8217;s Principal Keyboardist, Joanne Pearce Martin has performed worldwide as a soloist, chamber musician, and recording artist under such conductors as Esa-Pekka Salonen, John Adams, and Miguel Harth-Bedoya. She is also a frequent soloist with the LA Philharmonic during the summer Hollywood Bowl seasons and has appeared as guest soloist with orchestras including the Philadelphia Orchestra, L.A. Chamber Orchestra, San Diego Chamber Orchestra, Florida West Coast Symphony, and England&#8217;s Huddersfield Philharmonic. In great demand as a collaborative artist, Pearce Martin has performed with such artists as Joshua Bell, Lynn Harrell, Iona Brown, Jean-Pierre Rampal, Julius Baker, Aaron Rosand, &amp; Joseph Silverstein, among others.</p>
<p>In addition, Pearce Martin and her husband, pianist Gavin Martin, have continued to concertize together as a 2-piano team. She has also performed multiple-piano works with Emmanuel Ax, Yefim Bronfman, Helene Grimaud, and Jeffrey Kahane. A renowned artist hailed by the Los Angeles Times for playing with &#8220;unusual fervor and fluency,&#8221; Pearce Martin has performed on all major U.S. television networks and recorded commercially for Centaur, Summit, and Albany records, as well as the Yamaha Disklavier Piano recording software.</p>
<p>The subject of a half-hour feature on The Learning Channel, Pearce Martin&#8217;s latest recording project, &#8220;Joanne Pearce Martin, Barefoot&#8221;, was released in Spring 2008 on Yarlung Records. &#8220;This one is a true gem,&#8221; wrote Orrin Howard of CD Baby. &#8220;From the classically powerful to the transcendently modern, Joanne can do it all.&#8221;</p>
<p>ABOUT PACIFIC SERENADES<br />
Founded in 1982, Pacific Serenades is one of the longest performing ensembles on the west coast, featuring many of the most acclaimed musicians in Southern California -including principals from the Los Angeles Philharmonic, Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra, The Pasadena Symphony and the Long Beach Symphony. Yet, while most chamber ensembles offer either all-new music or all-traditional repertoire, Pacific Serenades makes a point of including both at each concert.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s very important for people to hear-and play-a new piece in the context of masterpieces of the past,&#8221; says founder Mark Carlson. &#8220;I really want new music to be heard as part of an ongoing tradition, rather than as a new art form with no roots.&#8221;</p>
<p>By June 2009, Pacific Serenades will have commissioned and premiered 94 new works by 51 different composers, with many of these works receiving as many as 50-60 additional performances worldwide following their premieres. Carlson, himself, is the recipient of more than 40 commissions and has composed works for the National Shrine in Washington, DC and the New West Symphony, among others, as well as many individual musicians.</p>
<p>Concerts currently take place at three venues, each selected to replicate the smaller, more intimate environment in which chamber music historically was performed: the Neighborhood Church in Pasadena; the UCLA Faculty Center; and a private home in Los Angeles. In addition, Pacific Serenades gave its first New York concert, at Carnegie Recital Hall, in September of 1994, and its first San Francisco concert in January of 1998.</p>
<p>Recently, Pacific Serenades won its second Adventurous Programming Award from ASCAP and Chamber Music America, in addition to a CMA/WQXR Record Award, in 2001, for its first CD, Mark Carlson&#8217;s The Hall of Mirrors. The ensemble&#8217;s latest CD, Border Crossings &#8211; featuring new works by Enrique Gonzalez-Medina, Robert Livingston Aldridge, Mark Carlson, and Miguel del Aguila &#8211; illustrates how the composers &#8211; two, Latin American-born and two, overtly influenced by Latin American music &#8211; have artistically crossed the border between the United States and Latin America.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Latin-born composers brought those influences with them when they moved here, and the others of us actively went to Latin America, seeking them,&#8221; explains Carlson.</p>
<p>A third CD, entitled &#8220;War Scrap: that we may have peace&#8221;, will include music by John Steinmetz, Larry Lipkis, and Mark Carlson. CDs may be purchased through Pacific Serenades&#8217; website, www.pacser.org or by calling 213.534.3434.</p>
<p># # #</p>
<p>CALENDAR:<br />
PACIFIC SERENADES &#8211; &#8220;Music Among Friends&#8221;<br />
Brahms &#8211; Clarinet Trio in A minor, Op. 114<br />
Ravel &#8211; Sonata for Violin and Piano<br />
Mark Carlson &#8211; New work for clarinet, violin, cello and piano<br />
Saturday, March 21; 8 p.m.; private home in Tarzana<br />
Sunday, March 22; 4 p.m.; Neighborhood Church<br />
301 N. Orange Grove Blvd. in Pasadena<br />
Tuesday, March 24; 8 p.m.; UCLA Faculty Center<br />
405 N. Hilgard Ave. on the UCLA campus<br />
Soloists:<br />
Gary Gray, clarinet<br />
Roger Wilkie, violin<br />
David Speltz, cello<br />
Joanne Pearce Martin, piano<br />
Tickets: $32 (Neighborhood Church and UCLA Faculty Center)<br />
$55 (private home/reception)<br />
For more information, call 213.534.3434 or visit www.pacser.org</p>
<p>PHOTOS AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST</p>
<p>UPCOMING PROGRAMS FOR 2009 SEASON:</p>
<p>Circle of blue<br />
Saturday, May 2, 4:00 pm, The home of Susan Key &amp; Michael Pratt in Brentwood<br />
Sunday, May 3, 4:00 pm, The Neighborhood Church in Pasadena<br />
Tuesday, May 5, 8:00 pm, The UCLA Faculty Center</p>
<p>Ravel: String Quartet in F major<br />
Mozart: Duo in G major, K. 423, for violin &amp; viola<br />
Billy Childs: New Work for string quartet<br />
Our 93rd premiere!<br />
World Premiere-commissioned by Pacific Serenades<br />
Composer and jazz pianist Billy Childs has for years been blurring the lines between jazz and Western classical music.</p>
<p>Roberto Cani, violin<br />
Connie Kupka, violin<br />
David Walther, viola<br />
David Speltz, cello</p>
<p>Weaving of many strands<br />
Saturday, June 6, 4:00 pm, The home of John &amp; Barbara McLoughlin in Brentwood<br />
Sunday, June 7, 4:00 pm, The Neighborhood Church in Pasadena<br />
Tuesday, June 9, 8:00 pm, The UCLA Faculty Center</p>
<p>Dvorak: Piano Quintet in A major, Op. 81<br />
Haydn: Piano Trio in A major, H. XV:9<br />
Paul Chihara: New Work for piano quintet<br />
Our 94th premiere!<br />
World Premiere-commissioned by Pacific Serenades<br />
A versatile and eclectic composer, Paul Chihara is equally at home composing for the San Francisco Ballet, the Broadway stage, film and television, and the concert hall.</p>
<p>Miwako Watanabe, violin<br />
Connie Kupka, violin<br />
Roland Kato, viola<br />
David Speltz, cello<br />
Edith Orloff, piano</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/press/pacific-serenades-presents-world-premiere-of-mark-carlsons-view-from-a-hilltop/">Pacific Serenades Presents World Premiere of Mark Carlson&#8217;s View from a Hilltop</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2009 Season Features Piece for Turkish Ud, Flute and String Trio by LA Composer Münir Beken</title>
		<link>http://pacser.org/press/2009-season-features-piece-for-turkish-ud-flute-and-string-trio-by-la-composer-munir-beken/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Heather Henderson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2009 04:21:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pacser.org/?post_type=press&#038;p=276</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Award winning chamber ensemble Pacific Serenades opens 2009 season with &#8220;The World Is Our Community&#8221; featuring works by Beethoven and ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/press/2009-season-features-piece-for-turkish-ud-flute-and-string-trio-by-la-composer-munir-beken/">2009 Season Features Piece for Turkish Ud, Flute and String Trio by LA Composer Münir Beken</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Award winning chamber ensemble Pacific Serenades opens 2009 season with &#8220;The World Is Our Community&#8221; featuring works by Beethoven and Mozart plus Memories of a Shoehorn for ud, flute and string trio by LA composer Münir Beken</p>
<p>Saturday, February 7, 2009; 8 pm; at a private home in Valley Glen<br />
Sunday, February 8, 2009; 4 pm; The Neighborhood Church in Pasadena<br />
Tuesday, February 10, 2009; 8 pm; The UCLA Faculty Center<br />
Calendar Summary follows press release<br />
____________________________________________________________________________________________________________</p>
<p>LOS ANGELES, Calif. The composer John Steinmetz has referred to Pacific Serenades as one of his &#8220;favorite renegade organizations.&#8221; But, as the opening performances of its 23rd season &#8211; &#8220;The World Is Our Community,&#8221; which will take place on Saturday, February 7 at a private home in Valley Glen at 8 p.m.; Sunday, February 8 at the Neighborhood Church in Pasadena at 4 p.m.; and Tuesday, February 10 at the UCLA Faculty Center at 8 p.m. &#8211; proves yet again, the award-winning chamber ensemble has held fast to one tradition.</p>
<p>Since its founding in 1982, Pacific Serenades has made a point of including, in every program, not only music by classical music titans revered throughout the ages like Beethoven, Mozart and Brahms but new works by composers with ties to Southern California whose commissions are performed worldwide.</p>
<p>Receiving its World Premiere at the February series of concerts is Memories of a Shoehorn for ud, flute and string trio by Münir Beken, a former conductor of the State Conservatory Orchestra of Istanbul who moved to Los Angeles in 2007 to become Assistant Professor of Ethnomusicology at UCLA. Memories of a Shoehorn was inspired by the shoehorn Beken&#8217;s father, an amateur singer in Turkey, carried with him to musical gatherings at other peoples&#8217; homes, where he&#8217;d remove his shoes as custom dictated.</p>
<p>Also on the program are Beethoven&#8217;s String Trio in C minor, Op 9, No. 3 and Mozart&#8217;s Flute Quartet in D major, K. 285.</p>
<p>&#8220;I can&#8217;t think of a more wonderfully rebellious way to indicate the value of a new piece than to show that it is part of a long, rich tradition of beautiful music,&#8221; says Mark Carlson, Founder and Artistic Director of Pacific Serenades.</p>
<p>A composer whose recording of his works, &#8220;The Hall of Mirrors&#8221;, was a winner of the Chamber Music America/WQXR Record Awards for 2001, Carlson is also an accomplished flutist. Joining him in the performances of &#8220;The World Is Our Community&#8221; are violinist Kathleen Lenski, violist Roland Kato and David Speltz on cello.</p>
<p>Lenski, a founding member of the Angeles String Quartet &#8211; which won a Grammy Award in 2001 after recording the complete string quartets of Joseph Haydn for Philips Classics &#8211; has appeared as soloist with such orchestras as the Los Angeles Philharmonic, the Seattle Symphony, the San Francisco Symphony, and the St. Louis Symphony. She has also served as soloist and concertmaster of Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra as well as soloist and leader of the Oregon Bach Festival Chamber Orchestra.</p>
<p>Roland Kato, described by the Los Angeles Times as &#8220;a brilliant virtuoso, playing with the perfect combination of energy and eloquence,&#8221; has been a member of the Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra since 1976 and, in 1987, was appointed Principal Violist by Iona Brown. As a guest artist, Kato has performed with the Chamber Music Society of Lincoln Center and the New York New Music Ensemble and has appeared as a soloist at such festivals as the Festival Casals in Puerto Rico, the Grand Canyon Chamber Music Festival, the Oregon Bach Festival, and the Festival Internacional de Musica in Costa Rica, among many others. Kato&#8217;s transcription of Prokofiev&#8217;s Music for Children was recently given its New York premiere, while his arrangement of Ravel&#8217;s Mother Goose Suite was premiered at the Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts by the New Hampshire-based Apple Hill Chamber Players in Washington D.C.</p>
<p>As a member of the Musical Offering ensemble, cellist David Speltz has performed at the Library of Congress and Lincoln Center in Washington D.C., the Casals Festival in Puerto Rico, and recorded on the Nonesuch label. Here in Los Angeles, Speltz appears regularly not only with Pacific Serenades but in chamber music series throughout Southern California, including Chamber Music in Historic Sites, the Bing Chamber Music Series at Caltech, and series sponsored by the South Bay Chamber Music Society and the Los Angeles County Museum of Art. A member of the Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra during Sir Neville Marriner&#8217;s tenure, Speltz served as principal cellist of the California Chamber Symphony for eight seasons and, in 1989, was invited by Helmuth Rilling to serve as principal cellist of the Bachakademie in Stuttgart, Germany.</p>
<p>Münir Beken will join the ensemble for the World Premiere of Memories of a Shoehorn for ud, flute, and string trio. An accomplished master of the ud who has worked with many eminent artists of Turkish classical music, Beken has also performed compositions written especially for him by American composers Melodie Linhart, Eric Flesher, and Christopher Shainin.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Beken&#8217;s own composition is not his first venture pairing the ud &#8211; a pear-shaped, stringed instrument that is the predecessor of the lute &#8211; with western musical instruments. &#8220;It&#8217;s always a challenge to join the sounds of these instruments,&#8221; Beken readily acknowledges. &#8220;It&#8217;s like mixing olive oil and vinegar. No matter how much you shake the bottle, it separates, and you recognize the individual elements.&#8221;</p>
<p>Those &#8220;elements,&#8221; Beken explains, include Turkish scales and modes, plus ornamentations and rhythms inspired by traditional Turkish music.</p>
<p>&#8220;People love the established masterworks, and justifiably so,&#8221; adds Carlson. &#8220;But we also all have an intense desire to hear something of our own time and place. Unfortunately, many people feel alienated by some of the trends of contemporary music, and so their trust has to be re-won. But when they hear a new work that embraces melody in some fashion or another, their ears perk up.&#8221;</p>
<p>Tickets for the February 7 concert and post concert reception at a private home are available for $55/person. Tickets for performances at The Neighborhood Church in Pasadena and the UCLA Faculty Center are $32/person. Full time student tickets are available at the door only, at Neighborhood Church and UCLA, for $5. To purchase tickets or learn more about season subscriptions, visit www.pacser.org or call 213.534.3434.</p>
<p>The Neighborhood Church is located at 301 N. Orange Grove Blvd. in Pasadena. The Gamble House museum, next door to the church, offers a discounted tour at $8/person to Pacific Serenades patrons on concert dates only. Tours begin promptly at 2 pm and at 2:40 pm and last approximately one hour. Reservations are required and must be made at least 48 hours in advance of the concert date by calling 626.793.3334, ext. 16.</p>
<p>The UCLA Faculty Center is located at 405 N. Hilgard Ave. on the UCLA campus in Westwood. Parking is available for $9 in Lot 2. In addition, prior to each concert, dinner at the UCLA Faculty Center is available for Pacific Serenades patrons. Reservations can be made by calling 310.825.0877.</p>
<p>Directions and additional information about private home concerts are mailed to ticket holders upon receipt of their order.</p>
<p>The mission of Pacific Serenades is to generate new chamber music by commissioning works and presenting them alongside standard repertoire in intimate concert settings, emphasizing Southern California musicians. For more information about Pacific Serenades, its upcoming season, musicians and composers, visit www.pacser.org or call 213.534.3434.</p>
<p>ABOUT PACIFIC SERENADES<br />
Founded in 1982, Pacific Serenades is one of the longest performing ensembles on the west coast, featuring many of the most acclaimed musicians in Southern California -including principals from the Los Angeles Philharmonic, Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra, The Pasadena Symphony and the Long Beach Symphony. Yet, while most chamber ensembles offer either all-new music or all-traditional repertoire, Pacific Serenades makes a point of including both at each concert.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s very important for people to hear-and play-a new piece in the context of masterpieces of the past,&#8221; says founder Mark Carlson. &#8220;I really want new music to be heard as part of an ongoing tradition, rather than as a new art form with no roots.&#8221;</p>
<p>By June 2009, Pacific Serenades will have commissioned and premiered 94 new works by 51 different composers, with many of these works receiving as many as 50-60 additional performances worldwide following their premieres. Carlson, himself, is the recipient of more than 40 commissions and has composed works for the National Shrine in Washington, DC and the New West Symphony, among others, as well as many individual musicians.</p>
<p>Concerts currently take place at three venues, each selected to replicate the smaller, more intimate environment in which chamber music historically was performed: the Neighborhood Church in Pasadena; the UCLA Faculty Center; and a private home in Los Angeles. In addition, Pacific Serenades gave its first New York concert, at Carnegie Recital Hall, in September of 1994, and its first San Francisco concert in January of 1998.</p>
<p>Recently, Pacific Serenades won its second Adventurous Programming Award from ASCAP and Chamber Music America, in addition to a CMA/WQXR Record Award, in 2001, for its first CD, Mark Carlson&#8217;s The Hall of Mirrors. The ensemble&#8217;s latest CD, Border Crossings &#8211; featuring new works by Enrique Gonzalez-Medina, Robert Livingston Aldridge, Mark Carlson, and Miguel del Aguila &#8211; illustrates how the composers &#8211; two, Latin American-born and two, overtly influenced by Latin American music &#8211; have artistically crossed the border between the United States and Latin America.</p>
<p>&#8220;The Latin-born composers brought those influences with them when they moved here, and the others of us actively went to Latin America, seeking them,&#8221; explains Carlson.</p>
<p>A third CD, entitled &#8220;War Scrap: that we may have peace&#8221;, will include music by John Steinmetz, Larry Lipkis, and Mark Carlson. CDs may be purchased through Pacific Serenades&#8217; website, www.pacser.org or by calling 213.534.3434.</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/press/2009-season-features-piece-for-turkish-ud-flute-and-string-trio-by-la-composer-munir-beken/">2009 Season Features Piece for Turkish Ud, Flute and String Trio by LA Composer Münir Beken</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pacific Serenades Releases Latin Influenced Border Crossings Recording</title>
		<link>http://pacser.org/press/pacific-serenades-releases-latin-influenced-border-crossings-recording/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Heather Henderson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 04:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pacser.org/?post_type=press&#038;p=273</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>New CD Features Four Works Commissioned by the Leading Chamber Music Ensemble Four original Latin-influenced works by gifted contemporary composers Enrique ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/press/pacific-serenades-releases-latin-influenced-border-crossings-recording/">Pacific Serenades Releases Latin Influenced Border Crossings Recording</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>New CD Features Four Works Commissioned by the Leading Chamber Music Ensemble</p>
<p>Four original Latin-influenced works by gifted contemporary composers Enrique González-Medina, Robert Livingston Aldridge, Mark Carlson and Miguel del Aguila are featured on Border Crossings, a new recording from Pacific Serenades, one of the nation&#8217;s foremost chamber music ensembles. The Border Crossings title illustrates the idea that the composers, two Latin American-born and two overtly influenced by Latin American music, have artistically crossed the border &#8212; in both directions &#8212; between the United States and Latin America. Pacific Serenades&#8217; previous CD, The Hall of Mirrors, won the 2001 Chamber Music America/WQXR Records Awards.</p>
<p>According to Carlson, Pacific Serenades founder and artistic director, &#8220;All four of the pieces have strong Latin-American rhythms, including tangos, various Brazilian dances and songs, and the Venezuelan merengue. The Latin-born composers brought those influences with them when they moved here, and the others of us actively went seeking them.&#8221;</p>
<p>Pacific Serenades has commissioned some 90 world premieres by 48 different composers, including these four works, more than any other organization of its kind in the country. Founded in 1982, it is one of the longest performing ensembles on the west coast. Twice winner (2003 and 2005) of the prestigious Chamber Music America/ASCAP Award for Adventurous Programming, Pacific Serenades has achieved critical acclaim for its concerts at which new music is played alongside traditional chamber repertoire in intimate settings, including private homes. Among its musicians are principals of the Los Angeles Philharmonic, Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra, Pasadena Symphony and Long Beach Symphony. Carlson is the recipient of more than 40 commissions and has composed works for the National Shrine in Washington, DC and the New West Symphony, among others, and for many individual musicians.</p>
<p>BORDER CROSSINGS</p>
<p>Concierto barroco for flute, violin, cello and harpsichord by Tijuana-born composer Enrique González-Medina was inspired by the eponymous novel by Cuban writer Alejo Carpentier in which Domenico Scarlatti, George Frideric Handel and Antonio Vivaldi meet and improvise on their favorite instruments (harpsichord, organ and violin). Gonzalez-Medina creates his own original baroque musical style that combines traditional forms of the baroque period, Spanish baroque and Latin American dances. Concierto barroco was commissioned by Jack and Florence Irving in 2002 for Pacific Serenades. González-Medina recently completed his first piano concerto which was commissioned by the Baja California Orchestra. The Baja California Songbook, 25 song settings of poems by five Baja poets, was premiered in 2006, and his children&#8217;s opera, How Nanita Learned to Make Flan, commissioned by Cincinnati Opera, has had more than 150 performances in the US. Guitarist Felix Bullock introduced González-Medina&#8217;s Medellin Concerto in Colombia, and Mexican soprano Claudia Montiel and guitarist Carlos Bernal recorded his song cycle, The Teacher&#8217;s Verses, for their CD, La Cuerda del Tiempo.</p>
<p>&#8220;If Bach used French, Italian, and German styles incorporated into the distinct movements of a suite, then I thought I should be able to do so with Irish, African, and Brazilian music!&#8221; says Robert Livingston Aldridge (with a smile) of his Three Folksongs for clarinet and string quartet. Each movement evolves from various &#8220;ethnic&#8221; themes: a Scotch/Irish ballad in sonata form, variations on an African-American-styled spiritual and a Brazilian samba realized as a rondo. Aldridge composed Three Folksongs in 1992 when it was commissioned by Elizabeth H. Henderson for Pacific Serenades. Aldridge&#8217;s music for orchestra, opera, dance, music-theater and chamber ensembles has been performed throughout the US, Europe and Japan. His tone poem Leda and the Swan, a four-orchestra consortium commission, was premiered in 2003, and his opera Elmer Gantry had its premiere at Nashville Opera in 2007. A clarinet concerto, commissioned by the Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra and Orpheus Chamber Orchestra, premiered in 2005.</p>
<p>Pacific Serenade for clarinet and string quartet by Miguel Del Aguila, is a romantic, peaceful work inspired by the Pacific Serenades ensemble, which premiered the piece in 1998. Its sensuousness is created by Latin song elements, especially nostalgic Brazilian folk songs, combined at times with blues-style melody and harmony. The string quartet, which is technically challenging, not only accompanies the clarinet, but also sets the mood in which the clarinet &#8220;sings&#8221; its serenade. It was commissioned by Dr. Eberhardt and Deedee Rechtin. Del Aguila, born in Uruguay, studied at the San Francisco Conservatory of Music and in Vienna. Upon returning to California in 1992, he was named &#8220;resident music man of the year&#8221; by the Los Angles Times. He has composed opera, choral, solo and chamber works as well as incidental music for theater and film. He was resident composer and music director of Ojai Camerata and resident composer at the Chautauqua Institution Summer Festival and is currently composer-in-residence with the New Mexico Symphony Orchestra in Albuquerque.</p>
<p>The eclectic Sonata for Cello and Piano reflects Mark Carlson&#8217;s diverse musical roots and interests, particularly South American popular music. The opening movement is sometimes agitated and busy while the last is inspired by the rhythm and form of the merengue, a dance peculiar to Venezuela. The middle movement begins in relative calm, then a high singing melody on the cello becomes slightly anguished, and finally calm is restored as the movement ends. Carlson composed the piece especially for cellist David Speltz and pianist Joanne Pearce Martin, who perform it on this recording. Commissioned by Virgil and Lynn Roth, it was premiered by Pacific Serenades in 1998. Always versatile, Carlson has composed lyrical and emotionally powerful, stylistically unique works which have been acclaimed by audiences throughout the US, Canada, Mexico and Europe. He is known for his art songs and songs for musical theater, chamber and choral music, concerti and other large ensemble pieces.</p>
<p>The Border Crossing recording features musicians Joanne Pearce Martin, principal keyboardist of the Los Angeles Philharmonic; Gary Gray, principal clarinetist and soloist of the Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra, Roland Kato, internationally acclaimed recitalist and soloist and principal violist for the Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra; violinist Roger Wilkie, concertmaster of the Long Beach Symphony; Clayton Haslop, first violinist with the Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra; violist Simon Oswell, principal violist of the Carmel Bach Festival and the Hollywood Bowl Orchestra; Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra violinist Connie Kupka; harpsichordist Patricia Mabee, who has been soloist and principal keyboardist for the Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra and a regular performer at a variety of music festivals; David Speltz, who helped form the Arriaga String Quartet which won first prize in the Coleman competition, violinist Miwako Watanabe, a founding member of the Sequoia Quartet and of the New Francesco Trio who appears regularly as concertmaster of the Chamber Orchestra of South Bay; and Pacific Serenades Founder/Artistic Director Mark Carlson, flute.</p>
<p>The recording was funded by The Argosy Foundation Contemporary Music Fund and The Aaron Copland Fund for Recording.</p>
<p>Border Crossings is available at Amazon.com, on the Pacific Serenades web site &#8212; www.pacser.org/store &#8211; or by calling (213) 534-3434.</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/press/pacific-serenades-releases-latin-influenced-border-crossings-recording/">Pacific Serenades Releases Latin Influenced Border Crossings Recording</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pacific Serenades Presents American Premiere of Jake Heggie&#8217;s Friendly Persuasion For Tenor and Baroque Ensemble</title>
		<link>http://pacser.org/press/pacific-serenades-presents-american-premiere-of-jake-heggies-friendly-persuasion-for-tenor-and-baroque-ensemble/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Heather Henderson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2008 04:15:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pacser.org/?post_type=press&#038;p=270</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>90th Work Commissioned and Premiered by the Leading Chamber Ensemble Closes 22nd Season Heggie&#8217;s Piece, a Co-Commission with London&#8217;s Wigmore Hall, Features ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/press/pacific-serenades-presents-american-premiere-of-jake-heggies-friendly-persuasion-for-tenor-and-baroque-ensemble/">Pacific Serenades Presents American Premiere of Jake Heggie&#8217;s Friendly Persuasion For Tenor and Baroque Ensemble</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>90th Work Commissioned and Premiered by the Leading Chamber Ensemble Closes 22nd Season</p>
<p>Heggie&#8217;s Piece, a Co-Commission with London&#8217;s Wigmore Hall, Features Tenor Nicholas Phan</p>
<p>Saturday, May 31, 2008, 4 pm, at a residence in Hancock Park<br />
Sunday, June 1, 2008, 4 pm, at The Neighborhood Church in Pasadena<br />
Tuesday, June 3, 2008, 8 pm, at The UCLA Faculty Center</p>
<p>The American premiere of Friendly Persuasions, a new work for tenor and Baroque ensemble by acclaimed composer Jake Heggie, is presented by the leading chamber ensemble Pacific Serenades to close its 22nd season on Saturday, May 31, 4 p.m., at a private home in Hancock Park; Sunday, June 1, 4 p.m., at The Neighborhood Church in Pasadena; and Tuesday, June 3, 8 p.m., at The UCLA Faculty Center. The piece is a co-commission by Pacific Serenades and London&#8217;s Wigmore Hall, recognized throughout the world for its early music, chamber music, song and jazz performances. Pacific Serenades, led by Founder and Artistic Director Mark Carlson, presented three world premieres earlier this season, bringing to 90 the number of works (by 48 different composers) the ensemble has commissioned and presented since its inception, more than any other organization of its kind in the country.</p>
<p>Friendly Persuasions&#8217; world premiere at Wigmore Hall was performed April 9 in a version for tenor and piano. The Pacific Serenades version for tenor and a baroque ensemble of flute, oboe, cello and harpsichord was commissioned by William Sullivan and Gerald Goodman for Pacific Serenades.</p>
<p>Nicholas Phan, who is quickly establishing himself as an important tenor among America&#8217;s next generation of singers, is featured in the concert series, titled The soul of lyricism, which also includes J.S. Bach&#8217;s selected arias for tenor with flute and oboe obbligato and basso continuo and Sonata in B minor, BWV 1030, for flute and harpsichord; Handel&#8217;s Trio Sonata in F major, Op. 2, No. 4, for flute, oboe, and basso continuo; and Vivaldi&#8217;s Sonata in C minor, RV 53, for oboe and basso continuo. Also performing are Mark Carlson, flute, Leslie Reed, oboe, David Speltz, cello, and Patricia Mabee, harpsichord.</p>
<p>Heggie, whose song cycles and operas are championed internationally, describes the genesis of the work by saying, &#8220;The pianist in London, Malcolm Martineau, was doing a survey of music by Francis Poulenc and asked me to write a set of songs as an homage to the great composer. Poulenc has been a major influence in my music for a long time.&#8221; The work is comprised of four songs, each based on a pivotal friendship in Poulenc&#8217;s life, including Wanda Landowska, greatly responsible for the revival of interest in the harpsichord as a solo instrument in the 20th Century, Raymonde Linossier, celebrated baritone Pierre Bernac, and poet Paul Eluard. &#8220;The stories about Poulenc&#8217;s friendships touched me because of their universal resonance,&#8221; adds Heggie.</p>
<p>Carlson and Heggie met as students many years ago at UCLA, and Heggie and Phan have also known each other for some time. &#8220;I really admire Mark and what he has done to support composers,&#8221; notes Heggie. &#8220;We all look for people who are going to help us go on in our lives. That&#8217;s why this piece seemed like a good fit for Pacific Serenades.&#8221; Regarding Phan, he says, &#8220;I wrote a song cycle for him, which was premiered at Ravinia in 2005. He&#8217;s got a lot of character, and I really love his voice.&#8221;</p>
<p>Composer of the acclaimed opera Dead Man Walking, Heggie has written more than 200 songs as well as concerti, orchestral works and chamber music. Among the artists with whom he&#8217;s collaborated are singers Audra McDonald, Patti LuPone and Zheng Cao, conductor Nicholas McGegan and director Leonard Foglia. His numerous commissions include works for the San Francisco Opera, Houston Grand Opera, Metropolitan Opera with Lincoln Center Theater, Opera Colorado, Ravinia Festival, Philharmonia Baroque Orchestra, St. Paul Chamber Orchestra, Carnegie Hall, Los Angeles Philharmonic and Louisville Orchestra, among many others, and individual commissions from singers Frederica von Stade, Jennifer Larmore, Bryn Terfel and Robert Orth.</p>
<p>Nicholas Phan, according to the Chicago Tribune, &#8220;is a rising star to be watched.&#8221; Among Phan&#8217;s engagements are his debuts at the New York City Opera, the Los Angeles Opera, the Chicago Opera Theater, the Arizona Opera, the New York City Opera, the Atlanta Opera, the Frankfurt Opera, Opera de Lille, the Rheingau Musik Festival, the Marlboro Festival, and the St. Louis Symphony, and a concert of songs by Jake Heggie with Heggie at the piano at Cal Performance in Berkeley. A graduate of the Houston Grand Opera Studio, Phan appeared in many productions there. He made his professional operatic debut with Glimmerglass Opera as a member of its Young American Artist Program. He was also a member of the Wolf Trap Opera. Phan made his Carnegie Hall (Stern Auditorium) debut in a performance of a new piece commissioned by the University of Michigan Symphony Orchestra.</p>
<p>PACIFIC SERENADES has become one of the foremost chamber music organizations in the nation since its inception in 1982 and one of the longest performing on the west coast. Twice winner (2003 and 2005) of the prestigious Chamber Music America/ASCAP Award for Adventurous Programming, the ensemble has achieved critical acclaim for its concerts at which new music is played alongside traditional chamber repertoire in intimate settings, including private homes. Among its musicians are principals of the Los Angeles Philharmonic, Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra, Pasadena Symphony and Long Beach Symphony. Pacific Serenades&#8217; CD, The Hall of Mirrors, won the 2001 Chamber Music America/WQXR Records Awards. Border Crossings, a new recording funded by The Argosy Foundation Contemporary Music Fund and The Aaron Copland Fund for Recording, was released in mid-2008. Pacific Serenades was founded by flutist and composer MARK CARLSON, who serves as artistic director. Carlson is the recipient of more than 40 commissions and has composed works for the National Shrine in Washington, DC, the New West Symphony, Westwood Presbyterian Church, First Methodist Church of Santa Monica, the UCLA Wind Ensemble, the Santa Monica College Orchestra, among others, and for many individual musicians.</p>
<p>The Neighborhood Church in Pasadena is located at 301 N. Orange Grove Boulevard in Pasadena, the UCLA Faculty Center is located at 405 N. Hilgard Avenue in Westwood. Directions to the Hancock Park concert (which is open to the public) will be sent to ticket buyers prior to the performance.</p>
<p>Pacific Serenades concerts are supported in part by the Los Angeles County Arts Commission and by Los Angeles Center Studios and Keyboard Concepts.</p>
<p>Tickets are $55 (home concert, including a post-concert reception) and $32 (Neighborhood Church and UCLA Faculty Center concerts). Student rush tickets are available for $5 (at the door only) for programs held at the Neighborhood Church in Pasadena and the UCLA Faculty Center. To purchase tickets, more information, or to request a brochure, call (213) 534-3434.</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/press/pacific-serenades-presents-american-premiere-of-jake-heggies-friendly-persuasion-for-tenor-and-baroque-ensemble/">Pacific Serenades Presents American Premiere of Jake Heggie&#8217;s Friendly Persuasion For Tenor and Baroque Ensemble</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pacific Serenades World Premieres Jeremy Cavaterra&#8217;s Fantasy For Four Instruments</title>
		<link>http://pacser.org/press/pacific-serenades-world-premieres-jeremy-cavaterras-fantasy-for-four-instruments/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Heather Henderson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2008 04:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pacser.org/?post_type=press&#038;p=260</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Saturday, April 26, 4 pm, at a Tarzana residence Sunday, April 27, 4 pm, at the Neighborhood Church in Pasadena ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/press/pacific-serenades-world-premieres-jeremy-cavaterras-fantasy-for-four-instruments/">Pacific Serenades World Premieres Jeremy Cavaterra&#8217;s Fantasy For Four Instruments</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Saturday, April 26, 4 pm, at a Tarzana residence<br />
Sunday, April 27, 4 pm, at the Neighborhood Church in Pasadena<br />
Tuesday, April 29, 8 pm, at the UCLA Faculty Center</p>
<p>Pacific Serenades, one of the West Coast&#8217;s leading chamber ensembles, presents the world premiere of composer Jeremy Cavaterra&#8217;s Fantasy for Four Instruments on Saturday, April 26, 4 p.m., at a Tarzana residence; Sunday, April 27, 4 p.m., at the Neighborhood Church in Pasadena; and Tuesday, April 29, 8 p.m., at the UCLA Faculty Center. Cavaterra is a noted composer and orchestrator of music for television, film, and the concert hall. His piano suite, Six Character Pieces, recently received its Los Angeles and San Francisco premieres by Spanish virtuoso Gustavo Díaz-Jerez, with whom Cavaterra has enjoyed a long musical collaboration.</p>
<p>In addition to the world premiere, the Pacific Serenades program, titled Dark woods and gleaming cities, also features Schumann&#8217;s Märchenbilder (Fairytale Pictures), Op. 113, for viola and piano; Debussy&#8217;s Premiere Rhapsodie for clarinet and piano, 1910; Glinka&#8217;s Trio pathétique in D minor, for clarinet, bassoon, and piano; and Tansman&#8217;s Suite for bassoon and piano. Gary Gray, clarinet, Judith Farmer, bassoon, Roland Kato, viola, and Ayke Agus, piano, are the performers.</p>
<p>Cavaterra describes his work as &#8220;a kind of ballet for instruments in which lyrical gestures and vigorous rhythms play, wrangle, or even strive violently against each other. Both sides win, happily.&#8221; About its genesis, he says, &#8220;[Pacific Serenades Founder and Artistic Director] Mark Carlson gave me the choice of writing for a string quartet or piano, clarinet, bassoon and viola, and I picked the latter, which in the end made it harder to write. These instruments &#8212; piano excluded &#8212; tend toward mid- to low ranges and dark, somber colors. While this afforded lots of rich, deep sonorities, it challenged me to find space and sweep without taking the instruments far from where they speak best. I focused on the strengths and charms of the particular instruments at hand, both individually and as a group, instead of miscasting them in roles they couldn&#8217;t perform, and the result is a piece that moves between dark and light.&#8221;</p>
<p>Pacific Serenades, led by Carlson, presents four world premieres during its 2008 season in keeping with its mission to commission new works each year. By the end of this season in June, the ensemble will have commissioned and presented 90 world premieres by 48 different composers since its inception, more than any other organization of its kind in the country.</p>
<p>PACIFIC SERENADES has become one of the foremost chamber music organizations in the nation since its inception in 1982 and one of the longest performing on the west coast. Twice winner (2003 and 2005) of the prestigious Chamber Music America/ASCAP Award for Adventurous Programming, the ensemble has achieved critical acclaim for its concerts at which new music is played alongside traditional chamber repertoire in intimate settings, including private homes. Among its musicians are principals of the Los Angeles Philharmonic, Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra, Pasadena Symphony and Long Beach Symphony. Pacific Serenades&#8217; CD, The Hall of Mirrors, won the 2001 Chamber Music America/WQXR Records Awards. A new recording, funded by The Argosy Foundation Contemporary Music Fund and The Aaron Copland Fund for Recording, is planned for the 2008 season. Pacific Serenades was founded by flutist and composer MARK CARLSON, who serves as artistic director. Carlson is the recipient of more than 40 commissions and has composed works for the National Shrine in Washington, DC, New West Symphony, Westwood Presbyterian Church, First Methodist Church of Santa Monica, UCLA Wind Ensemble, Santa Monica College Orchestra, among others, and for many individual musicians.</p>
<p>JEREMY CAVATERRA was born in New York City in 1971. Interested in music from an early age, he began improvising and &#8220;composing&#8221; on the piano long before receiving any formal musical training. When he was ten his family moved to L.A., and he took piano lessons with Tania Agins who gave him a firm traditional foundation and also encouraged his interest in composition, introducing him to Mark Carlson who guided his efforts and also provided him with theory lessons. Later he furthered his piano studies with Robert Turner before receiving a full scholarship to attend Manhattan School of Music in New York where he studied composition with Giampaolo Bracali as well as orchestration and conducting. He spent the next several years in Italy composing and performing as pianist in and around Rome and participating in festivals such as Musica Contemporanea Lazio and Musica sotto l&#8217;Orologio in which his works were premièred. Returning to L.A., he worked as composer and orchestrator for a number of films and television shows before deciding that his temperament and a distaste for electronics indisposed him to the commercial music business. More recently he has shifted his emphasis back to his musical roots, composing concert music for live players, the ambit in which he is happiest. Cavaterra is also an author whose work has appeared in publications as diverse as music journals and science fiction magazines.</p>
<p>The Neighborhood Church in Pasadena is located at 301 N. Orange Grove Boulevard in Pasadena, the UCLA Faculty Center is located at 405 N. Hilgard Avenue in Westwood. Directions to the concert in Tarzana (which is open to the public) will be sent to ticket buyers prior to the performance.</p>
<p>Pacific Serenades concerts are supported in part by the Los Angeles County Arts Commission and by Los Angeles Center Studios and Keyboard Concepts.</p>
<p>Tickets are $55 (home concert) and $32 (Neighborhood Church and UCLA Faculty Center concerts). Student rush tickets are available for $5 (at the door only) for programs held at the Neighborhood Church in Pasadena and the UCLA Faculty Center. To purchase tickets, more information, or to request a brochure, call (213) 534-3434. www.pacser.org.</p>
<p>EDITORS PLEASE NOTE: PACIFIC SERENADES Dark woods and gleaming cities<br />
Saturday, April 26, 4 pm, at a Tarzana residence, Sunday, April 27, 4 pm, at The Neighborhood Church Pasadena, Tuesday, April 29, 8 pm, at The UCLA Faculty Center</p>
<p>Schumann Märchenbilder (Fairytale Pictures), Op. 113, for viola and piano<br />
Debussy Premiere Rhapsodie for clarinet and piano, 1910<br />
Glinka Trio pathétique in D minor, for clarinet, bassoon, and piano<br />
Tansman Suite for bassoon and piano<br />
Jeremy Cavaterra Fantasy for Four Instruments World Premiere commissioned by Pacific Serenades</p>
<p>Gary Gray, clarinet Judith Farmer, bassoon<br />
Roland Kato, viola Ayke Agus, piano</p>
<p>Tickets are $55 (home concert) and $32 (Neighborhood Church and UCLA Faculty Center concerts). Student rush tickets are available for $5 (at the door only) for programs held at the Neighborhood Church in Pasadena and the UCLA Faculty Center. To purchase tickets, more information, or to request a brochure, call (213) 534-3434.</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/press/pacific-serenades-world-premieres-jeremy-cavaterras-fantasy-for-four-instruments/">Pacific Serenades World Premieres Jeremy Cavaterra&#8217;s Fantasy For Four Instruments</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>22nd Season Continues With World Premiere of New Work for Violin and Piano by Composer Bruce Boughton</title>
		<link>http://pacser.org/press/22nd-season-continues-with-world-premiere-of-new-work-for-violin-and-piano-by-composer-bruce-boughton/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Heather Henderson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2008 03:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pacser.org/?post_type=press&#038;p=250</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160; Saturday, March 1, 8 pm, at a private home in Brentwood Sunday, March 2, 4 pm, at The Neighborhood ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/press/22nd-season-continues-with-world-premiere-of-new-work-for-violin-and-piano-by-composer-bruce-boughton/">22nd Season Continues With World Premiere of New Work for Violin and Piano by Composer Bruce Boughton</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Saturday, March 1, 8 pm, at a private home in Brentwood<br />
Sunday, March 2, 4 pm, at The Neighborhood Church in Pasadena<br />
Tuesday, March 4, 8 pm, at The UCLA Faculty Center</p>
<p>Pacific Serenades, one of the West Coast&#8217;s leading chamber ensembles, continues its 22nd season with its 88th world premiere, Bruce Broughton&#8217;s Sonata for Violin and Piano. One of the most versatile composers working today, Broughton wrote the piece for his wife, violinist Belinda Broughton, who performs it with pianist Joanne Pearce Martin on Saturday, March 1, 8 p.m., at a private home in Brentwood; Sunday, March 2, 4 p.m., at The Neighborhood Church in Pasadena; and Tuesday, March 4, 8 p.m., at The UCLA Faculty Center.</p>
<p>Pacific Serenades founder and artistic director Mark Carlson describes the new work by multiple Emmy winner and Grammy and Oscar nominee Bruce Broughton as rousing in the fast movements with a lyrical and moving slow movement. It displays perfectly Belinda&#8217;s virtuosic skills.&#8221;</p>
<p>In addition to the Broughton world premiere, the concert program, titled Mavericks and magicians, features Debussy&#8217;s Sonata for cello and piano (1915), one of the last three pieces he wrote, and Mendelssohn&#8217;s rarely performed Piano Trio in C minor, Op. 66, featuring cellist David Speltz with Belinda Broughton and Joanne Pearce Martin. &#8220;Debussy is the &#8216;maverick&#8217; of the program,&#8221; Carlson says, &#8220;in terms of the piece&#8217;s unique form offering different colors from those usually heard in works for cello and piano. As for &#8216;magicians,&#8217; Mendelssohn&#8217;s piano trio has a playfulness to it, and although it&#8217;s often overshadowed by his signature Piano Trio, No. 1 in D minor, this work is equally stunning.&#8221;</p>
<p>Broughton writes in every medium, from theatrical releases and TV feature films to the concert stage and computer games. An accomplished composer of concert music, he has conducted and recorded numerous original works written for ensembles ranging from the Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra and the Chicago, Seattle and National Symphonies to the United States Air Force Band. His first major film score, for the Lawrence Kasdan western Silverado, brought him an Oscar nomination, and the soundtrack album for his subsequent project, a classically styled score for Barry Levinson&#8217;s Young Sherlock Holmes, earned a Grammy nomination. With over 20 Emmy nominations, Broughton has received a record ten, including for Glory &amp; Honor; O Pioneers! and Dallas He conducted and supervised the recording of Gershwin&#8217;s &#8220;Rhapsody In Blue&#8221; for Disney&#8217;s Fantasia 2000, and his score for &#8220;Heart Of Darkness&#8221; was the first orchestral score composed for a video game. Broughton&#8217;s first world premiere for Pacific Serenades was A Primer for Malachi, a work for flute, clarinet, cello, and piano, in 1997.</p>
<p>Belinda Broughton began performing concertos as a child with the New Zealand Symphony Orchestra, and at the age of 12, she performed the Mendelssohn Concerto for Queen Elizabeth II at a Royal Command performance in New Zealand. At 18, she joined the London Philharmonic Orchestra as its youngest ever member and the following year was also playing as assistant concertmaster with the London Symphony Orchestra and BBC Symphony Orchestra. By the age of 20 she had performed as concertmaster with the Royal Opera House Covent Garden, English National Opera and BBC Concert Orchestra.</p>
<p>Pacific Serenades, led by Founder and Artistic Director Mark Carlson, presents four world premieres during its 2008 season. By the end of the season, the ensemble will have commissioned and presented 90 world premieres by 48 different composers since its inception, more than any other organization of its kind in the country.</p>
<p>Composer BRUCE BROUGHTON&#8217;s major motion picture credits include Lost in Space; Tombstone; Miracle on 34th Street; Carried Away; Baby&#8217;s Day Out; The Presidio; Narrow Margin; Harry and The Hendersons; Krippendorf&#8217;s Tribe; Honey, I Blew Up The Kid; The Boy Who Could Fly; the Disney animated features, The Rescuers Down Under and Bambi II, and the two Homeward Bound adventures. He conducted and supervised the recording of Gershwin&#8217;s &#8220;Rhapsody In Blue&#8221; for Fantasia 2000. Numerous TV credits include the main titles for JAG, Tiny Toon Adventures, and Dinosaurs, as well as scores for Amazing Stories, Quincy, and How The West Was Won. Movies for television include Lucy, Bobbie&#8217;s Girl, and O Pioneers!; and the miniseries Roughing It, The Blue and the Gray, and the Emmy-nominated True Women. An accomplished composer of concert music, Broughton has conducted and recorded numerous original works, including &#8220;Mixed Elements,&#8221; commissioned by and premiered at the Sunflower Music Festival, &#8220;Modular Music,&#8221; composed for the Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra; &#8220;The Magic Horn,&#8221; commissioned jointly by the Chicago, Seattle and National Symphonies for the Magic Circle Mime Company; &#8220;Excursions,&#8221; commissioned and premiered by The United States Air Force Band in Washington, D.C.; &#8220;Fanfares, Marches, Hymns and Finale,&#8221; commissioned by The Bay Brass; &#8220;English Music&#8221; for Horn and Strings; &#8220;And on the Sixth Day&#8221; for oboe and orchestra; &#8220;Tyvek Wood,&#8221; commissioned by the Debussy Trio; a piccolo concerto; a tuba concerto; several solo works for winds; numerous chamber works, and the list goes on. As a conductor, his recordings of Miklós Rózsa&#8217;s Ivanhoe and Julius Caesar for Intrada records, performed by the Sinfonia of London shortly before the composer&#8217;s death, have received rave reviews, as has his recording of Bernard Herrmann&#8217;s riveting score for Jason and the Argonauts. Broughton is a board member of ASCAP, a governor of the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences, a former governor of the Academy of Television Arts and Sciences, and past president of The Society of Composers and Lyricists. He has taught film composition in the Advanced Film Music Studies program at USC and is a frequent lecturer at UCLA.</p>
<p>PACIFIC SERENADES has become one of the foremost chamber music organizations in the nation since its inception in 1982 and one of the longest performing on the west coast. Twice winner (2003 and 2005) of the prestigious Chamber Music America/ASCAP Award for Adventurous Programming, the ensemble has achieved critical acclaim for its concerts at which new music is played alongside traditional chamber repertoire in intimate settings, including private homes. Among its musicians are principals of the Los Angeles Philharmonic, Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra, Pasadena Symphony and Long Beach Symphony. Pacific Serenades&#8217; CD, The Hall of Mirrors, won the 2001 Chamber Music America/WQXR Records Awards. A new recording, funded by The Argosy Foundation Contemporary Music Fund and The Aaron Copland Fund for Recording, is planned for the coming season. Pacific Serenades was founded by flutist and composer MARK CARLSON, who serves as artistic director. Carlson is the recipient of more than 40 commissions and has composed works for the National Shrine in Washington, DC, the New West Symphony, Westwood Presbyterian Church, First Methodist Church of Santa Monica, the UCLA Wind Ensemble, the Santa Monica College Orchestra, among others, and for many individual musicians.</p>
<p>The Neighborhood Church in Pasadena is located at 301 N. Orange Grove Boulevard in Pasadena, the UCLA Faculty Center is located at 405 N. Hilgard Avenue in Westwood. Directions to the home concert in Brentwood (which is open to the public) will be sent to ticket buyers prior to the performance.</p>
<p>Pacific Serenades concerts are supported in part by the Los Angeles County Arts Commission and by The James Irvine Foundation, Los Angeles Center Studios and Keyboard Concepts.</p>
<p>Tickets are $55 (home concert) and $32 (Neighborhood Church and UCLA Faculty Center concerts). Student rush tickets are available for $5 (at the door only) for programs held at the Neighborhood Church in Pasadena and the UCLA Faculty Center. To purchase tickets, more information, or to request a brochure, call (213) 534-3434. www.pacser.org.</p>
<p>EDITORS PLEASE NOTE:</p>
<p>Mavericks and magicians<br />
Saturday, March 1, 8 pm, at a private home in Brentwood<br />
Sunday, March 2, 4 pm, at The Neighborhood Church in Pasadena<br />
Tuesday, March 4, 8 pm, at The UCLA Faculty Center</p>
<p>Mendelssohn: Piano Trio in C minor, Op. 66<br />
Debussy: Sonata for cello and piano (1915)<br />
Bruce Broughton: Sonata for violin and piano<br />
World Premiere-commissioned by Pacific Serenades</p>
<p>Belinda Broughton, violin<br />
David Speltz, cello<br />
Joanne Pearce Martin, piano</p>
<p>Tickets are $55 (home concert) and $32 (Neighborhood Church and UCLA Faculty Center concerts). Student rush tickets are available for $5 (at the door only) for programs held at the Neighborhood Church in Pasadena and the UCLA Faculty Center. To purchase tickets, more information, or to request a brochure, call (213) 534-3434.</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/press/22nd-season-continues-with-world-premiere-of-new-work-for-violin-and-piano-by-composer-bruce-boughton/">22nd Season Continues With World Premiere of New Work for Violin and Piano by Composer Bruce Boughton</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>22nd Season Begins With Jazz Trumpet Virtuoso John Daversa&#8217;s New Work for Flute and String Quartet</title>
		<link>http://pacser.org/press/22nd-season-begins-with-jazz-trumpet-virtuoso-john-daversas-new-work-for-flute-and-string-quartet/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Heather Henderson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2008 03:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pacser.org/?post_type=press&#038;p=248</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Saturday, January 26, 8 p.m., at a residence in Encino Sunday, January 27, 4 p.m., at The Neighborhood Church in ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/press/22nd-season-begins-with-jazz-trumpet-virtuoso-john-daversas-new-work-for-flute-and-string-quartet/">22nd Season Begins With Jazz Trumpet Virtuoso John Daversa&#8217;s New Work for Flute and String Quartet</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6></h6>
<p>Saturday, January 26, 8 p.m., at a residence in Encino<br />
Sunday, January 27, 4 p.m., at The Neighborhood Church in Pasadena<br />
Tuesday, January 29, 8 p.m., at The UCLA Faculty Center</p>
<p>Pacific Serenades, one of the West Coast&#8217;s leading chamber ensembles, opens its 22nd season with its 87th world premiere, &#8220;Between the Thoughts,&#8221; a new work for flute and string quartet by jazz trumpet virtuoso John Daversa, on Saturday, January 26, 8 p.m., at a residence in Encino; Sunday, January 27, 4 p.m., at The Neighborhood Church in Pasadena; and Tuesday, January 29, 8 p.m., at The UCLA Faculty Center. The program, titled To the victims of war, a dedication to life, also features two diverse masterpieces, Shostakovich&#8217;s String Quartet No. 8 in C minor, Op. 110, a work whose dedication reads &#8220;to the victims of fascism and war,&#8221; and Mendelssohn&#8217;s String Quartet in E minor, Op. 44, No. 2. By the end of the 2008 season, Pacific Serenades will have commissioned and presented 90 world premieres by 48 different composers since its inception, more than any other organization of its kind in the country.</p>
<p>Performing the program are Kathleen Lenski and Connie Kupka, violin, David Walther, viola, David Speltz, cello and Pacific Serenades Founder and Artistic Director Mark Carlson, flute. Lenski was a founding member and first violinist of the acclaimed Angeles String Quartet, which toured in the U.S. and abroad, recorded the complete string quartets of Joseph Haydn for Philips Classics and won the 2001 classical chamber music Grammy Award.</p>
<p>Daversa, a nationally-known Los Angeles-based jazz trumpet player and leader of the critically-acclaimed John Daversa Contemporary Big Band, faced a unique challenge reconciling jazz and other improvisatory music he has been influenced by with music for a classical chamber ensemble. Accustomed to writing and orchestrating for his own band, he used this opportunity to experiment with texture and color in a completely different context, resulting in &#8220;Between the Thoughts,&#8221; a song-form jazz tune evocative of the &#8220;Great American Songbook&#8221; of enduring popular tunes of the 1920s-1950s.</p>
<p>&#8220;In order to keep the orchestration as elastic as possible and the harmonic element of the work true to my own initial conception, I started with two interacting lines and added the other parts one by one,&#8221; Daversa says. &#8220;I wanted to find the balance between counterpoint and harmony that worked best for this piece and to find a way to allow the melody to weave in and out of the overall texture. In this respect, I took inspiration from a ballad, Most of All, that I wrote for my contemporary big band, which features the bass clarinet as the work&#8217;s principal voice.&#8221;</p>
<p>Daversa, the founder and leader of the John Daversa Big Band, is an active performer, composer, arranger, director, producer, and educator based in Los Angeles. He has performed or recorded with Bobby Caldwell, Glen Campbell, Dr. Dre, Paquito D&#8217;Rivera, Bob Florence, Dizzy Gillespie, J.J. Johnson, Andre Manga, Justin Morell, Renee Olstead, Bill Perkins, Kim Richmond, Lalo Schifrin, Jack Sheldon, Shogun Warrior, Solsonics, Andy Williams and Gerald Wilson. As a trumpeter, Daversa has won coveted awards and competitions, among them the Herb Alpert Award, the David Joel Miller Award, the National Trumpet Competition, and the ITG Jazz Soloist Competition. He was also a finalist in the prestigious Thelonious Monk International Jazz Competition. He has worked as an arranger/composer for Fiona Apple and the Gay Men&#8217;s Chorus of Los Angeles, among others.</p>
<p>Pacific Serenades presents three additional world premieres during its 2008 season.</p>
<p>PACIFIC SERENADES has become one of the foremost chamber music organizations in the nation since its inception in 1982 and one of the longest performing on the west coast. Twice winner (2003 and 2005) of the prestigious Chamber Music America/ASCAP Award for Adventurous Programming, the ensemble has achieved critical acclaim for its concerts at which new music is played alongside traditional chamber repertoire in intimate settings, including private homes. Among its musicians are principals of the Los Angeles Philharmonic, Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra, Pasadena Symphony and Long Beach Symphony. Pacific Serenades&#8217; CD, The Hall of Mirrors, won the 2001 Chamber Music America/WQXR Records Awards. A new recording, funded by The Argosy Foundation Contemporary Music Fund and The Aaron Copland Fund for Recording, is planned for the coming season. Pacific Serenades was founded by flutist and composer MARK CARLSON, who serves as artistic director. Carlson is the recipient of more than 40 commissions and has composed works for the National Shrine in Washington, DC, the New West Symphony, Westwood Presbyterian Church, First Methodist Church of Santa Monica, the UCLA Wind Ensemble, the Santa Monica College Orchestra, among others, and for many individual musicians.</p>
<p>The Neighborhood Church in Pasadena is located at 301 N. Orange Grove Boulevard in Pasadena, the UCLA Faculty Center is located at 405 N. Hilgard Avenue in Westwood. Directions to the home concert in Encino (which is open to the public) will be sent to ticket buyers prior to the performance.</p>
<p>Pacific Serenades concerts are supported in part by the Los Angeles County Arts Commission and by The James Irvine Foundation, Los Angeles Center Studios and Keyboard Concepts.</p>
<p>Season subscriptions are available for $175 (residence series) and $98 (Neighborhood Church and UCLA Faculty Center series), with special &#8220;Mix-and-Match Series&#8221; and other packages.</p>
<p>Single tickets are $55 for concerts in residences, which include refreshments, and $32 for concerts at the Neighborhood Church and UCLA Faculty Center. Student rush tickets are available for $5 (at the door only) for programs held at the Neighborhood Church and the UCLA Faculty Center. To purchase tickets, more information, or to request a brochure, call (213) 534-3434. www.pacser.org.</p>
<p>EDITORS PLEASE NOTE:</p>
<p>To the victims of war, a dedication to life<br />
Saturday, January 26, 8 pm, at a residence in Encino<br />
Sunday, January 27, 4 pm, at The Neighborhood Church in Pasadena<br />
Tuesday, January 29, 8 pm, at The UCLA Faculty Center</p>
<p>Shostakovich: String Quartet No. 8 in C minor, Op. 110<br />
Mendelssohn: String Quartet in E minor, Op. 44, No. 2<br />
John Daversa: &#8220;Between the Thoughts,&#8221; a new work for flute and string quartet<br />
(World Premiere-commissioned by Pacific Serenades)</p>
<p>Kathleen Lenski, violin<br />
Connie Kupka, violin<br />
David Walther, viola<br />
David Speltz, cello<br />
Mark Carlson, flute</p>
<p>Season subscriptions are available for $175 (residence series) and $98 (Neighborhood Church and UCLA Faculty Center series), with special &#8220;Mix-and-Match Series&#8221; and other packages. Single tickets are $55 for concerts in residences, which include refreshments, and $32 for concerts at the Neighborhood Church and UCLA Faculty Center. Student rush tickets are available for $5 (at the door only) for programs held at the Neighborhood Church and the UCLA Faculty Center. To purchase tickets, more information, or to request a brochure, call (213) 534-3434. www.pacser.org.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/press/22nd-season-begins-with-jazz-trumpet-virtuoso-john-daversas-new-work-for-flute-and-string-quartet/">22nd Season Begins With Jazz Trumpet Virtuoso John Daversa&#8217;s New Work for Flute and String Quartet</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>22nd Season Features 4 World Premieres</title>
		<link>http://pacser.org/press/22nd-season-features-4-world-premieres/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Heather Henderson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2007 03:20:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pacser.org/?post_type=press&#038;p=208</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jake Heggie&#8217;s Piece for Tenor and Baroque Ensemble (a Co-Commission with London&#8217;s Wigmore Hall) is 90th Work Commissioned by the ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/press/22nd-season-features-4-world-premieres/">22nd Season Features 4 World Premieres</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jake Heggie&#8217;s Piece for Tenor and Baroque Ensemble (a Co-Commission with London&#8217;s Wigmore Hall) is 90th Work Commissioned by the Leading Chamber Ensemble</p>
<p>New Music by Jazz Trumpet Virtuoso John Daversa, Academy Award Nominee Bruce Broughton, and Film/Television Composer and Orchestrator Jeremy Cavaterra Also World Premiered During Season</p>
<p>A new work for tenor and Baroque ensemble by Jake Heggie, whose song cycles and operas are championed internationally, is among four world premieres presented by Pacific Serenades, one of the West Coast&#8217;s leading chamber ensembles, during its 22nd season beginning in January 2008. The Heggie piece is a co-commission with London&#8217;s Wigmore Hall, the celebrated chamber music recital venue, and brings to 90 the number of works commissioned and presented by Pacific Serenades since its inception.</p>
<p>The 2008 season, featuring four concert programs, also includes world premieres of jazz trumpet virtuoso John Daversa&#8217;s new work for flute and string quartet, Academy and Grammy Award-nominee and multiple Emmy Award-winner Bruce Broughton&#8217;s new work for violin and piano, and film/television composer and orchestrator Jeremy Cavaterra&#8217;s new work for clarinet, bassoon, viola, and piano.</p>
<p>&#8220;This season&#8217;s adventures embrace the blurring of boundaries between jazz, film music, opera, and traditional chamber music,&#8221; says Pacific Serenades Founder and Artistic Director Mark Carlson. &#8220;Our programs offer works that balance the anguish of war with a commitment to life, pieces which seem to come out of the blue and others equally bold in using traditional forms, fairy tales right next to stories from modern Europe and America, and the soulfulness and joy that are Baroque music sharing the stage with modern words.&#8221;</p>
<p>Pacific Serenades, twice winner (2003 and 2005) of the prestigious Chamber Music America/ASCAP Award for Adventurous Programming, has achieved critical acclaim for its concerts at which new music is played alongside traditional chamber repertoire in intimate settings, including private homes. By the end of the 2008 season in June, the ensemble will have to its credit world premieres by 48 different composers, with the milestone 90th work well surpassing those commissioned and presented by any other organization of its kind in the country. Among Pacific Serenades&#8217; musicians are principals of the Los Angeles Philharmonic, Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra, Pasadena Symphony and Long Beach Symphony.</p>
<p>Pacific Serenades opens the 22nd season with a new work for flute and string quartet by John Daversa on Saturday, January 26, 8 p.m., at a private home in Encino; Sunday, January 27, 4 p.m., at The Neighborhood Church in Pasadena; and Tuesday, January 29, 8 p.m., at The UCLA Faculty Center. The program, titled To the victims of war, a dedication to life, also features Shostakovich&#8217;s String Quartet No. 8 in C minor, Op. 110, and Mendelssohn&#8217;s String Quartet in E minor, Op. 44, No. 2, performed by Kathleen Lenski and Connie Kupka, violin, David Walther, viola, David Speltz, cello and Mark Carlson, flute. Daversa, a jazz trumpet virtuoso and founder/leader of the John Daversa Big Band, is an active performer, composer, arranger, director, producer, and educator based in Los Angeles. Among those with whom he has performed or recorded are Bobby Caldwell, Glen Campbell, Dizzy Gillespie, Bill Perkins, Lalo Schifrin, Jack Sheldon, Andy Williams and Gerald Wilson.</p>
<p>The season&#8217;s second concert series, Mavericks and magicians, spotlights Bruce Broughton&#8217;s new work for violin and piano on Saturday, March 1, 8 p.m., at a private home in Brentwood; Sunday, March 2, 4 p.m., at The Neighborhood Church in Pasadena; and Tuesday, March 4, 8 p.m., at The UCLA Faculty Center. Mendelssohn&#8217;s Piano Trio in C minor, Op. 66, and Debussy&#8217;s Sonata for cello and piano (1915) are also on the program, performed by Belinda Broughton, violin, David Speltz, cello, and Joanne Pearce Martin, piano. Broughton, one of the most versatile composers working today, writes in every medium, from theatrical releases and TV feature films to the concert stage and computer games. His first major film score, for the Lawrence Kasdan western Silverado, brought him an Oscar nomination, and the soundtrack album for his next project, a classically styled score for Barry Levinson&#8217;s Young Sherlock Holmes, earned a Grammy nomination. With over 20 Emmy nominations, Broughton has received a record ten, including for Glory &amp; Honor; O Pioneers! and Dallas He conducted and supervised the recording of Gershwin&#8217;s &#8220;Rhapsody In Blue&#8221; for Disney&#8217;s Fantasia 2000, and his score for &#8220;Heart Of Darkness&#8221; was the first orchestral score composed for a video game. An accomplished composer of concert music, Broughton has conducted and recorded numerous original works written for ensembles ranging from the Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra and the Chicago, Seattle and National Symphonies to the United States Air Force Band.</p>
<p>Jeremy Cavaterra&#8217;s new work for clarinet, bassoon, viola, and piano is the centerpieces of Dark woods and gleaming cities on Saturday, April 26, 4 p.m., at a private home in Tarzana; Sunday, April 27, 4 p.m., at The Neighborhood Church in Pasadena; and Tuesday, April 29, 8 p.m., at The UCLA Faculty Center. The program also features Schumann&#8217;s Märchenbilder (Fairytale Pictures), Op. 113, for viola and piano; Debussy&#8217;s Premiere Rhapsodie for clarinet and piano, 1910; Glinka&#8217;s Trio pathétique in D minor, for clarinet, bassoon, and piano; and Tansman&#8217;s Suite for bassoon and piano. Gary Gray, clarinet, Judith Farmer, bassoon, Roland Kato, viola, and Ayke Agus, piano, are the performers. Cavaterra, composer and orchestrator of music for television, film, and the concert hall, is also a writer nearing completion of his first novel</p>
<p>Closing the 2008 season is Pacific Serenades&#8217; 90th premiere, a new work for tenor and baroque ensemble by Jake Heggie, composer of the acclaimed opera Dead Man Walking, on Saturday, May 31, 4 p.m., at a private home in Hancock Park; Sunday, June 1, 4 p.m., at The Neighborhood Church in Pasadena; and Tuesday, June 3, 8 p.m., at The UCLA Faculty Center. Heggie&#8217;s piece is a co-commission by Pacific Serenades and London&#8217;s Wigmore Hall, recognized throughout the world for the 400 events it presents each year including song, early music, chamber music and jazz. The concert series, titled The soul of lyricism, also includes selected arias for tenor with flute and oboe obbligato and basso continuo and Sonata in B minor, BWV 1030, for flute and harpsichord by J.S. Bach; Handel&#8217;s Trio Sonata in F major, Op. 2, No. 4, for flute, oboe, and basso continuo; and Vivaldi&#8217;s Sonata in C minor, RV 53, for oboe and basso continuo. Performers are Mark Carlson, flute, Leslie Reed, oboe, David Speltz, cello, and Patricia Mabee, harpsichord. Nicholas Phan is the tenor for the work by Heggie, who has composed more than 200 songs as well as concerti, orchestral works and chamber music. Among the artists with whom he&#8217;s collaborated are singers Audra McDonald, Patti LuPone and Zheng Cao, conductor Nicholas McGegan and director Leonard Foglia. His numerous commissions include works for the San Francisco Opera, Houston Grand Opera, Metropolitan Opera with Lincoln Center Theater, Opera Colorado, Ravinia Festival, Philharmonia Baroque Orchestra, St. Paul Chamber Orchestra, Carnegie Hall, Los Angeles Philharmonic and Louisville Orchestra, among many others, and individual commissions from singers Frederica von Stade, Jennifer Larmore, Bryn Terfel and Robert Orth.</p>
<p>Under Carlson&#8217;s direction, Pacific Serenades has become one of the foremost chamber music organizations in the nation since its inception in 1982 and one of the longest performing on the West Coast. Pacific Serenades&#8217; CD, The Hall of Mirrors, won the 2001 Chamber Music America/WQXR Records Awards. A new recording, funded by The Argosy Foundation Contemporary Music Fund and The Aaron Copland Fund for Recording, is being released during the 2008 season.</p>
<p>The Neighborhood Church in Pasadena is located at 301 N. Orange Grove Boulevard in Pasadena, the UCLA Faculty Center is located at 405 N. Hilgard Avenue in Westwood. Directions to the private home concerts (which are open to the public) are provided to ticket buyers prior to the performances.</p>
<p>Pacific Serenades concerts are supported in part by the Los Angeles County Arts Commission and by Los Angeles Center Studios and Keyboard Concepts.</p>
<p>Season subscriptions are available for $175 (private home series) and $98 (Neighborhood Church and UCLA Faculty Center series), with special &#8220;Mix-and-Match Series&#8221; and other packages. Single tickets are $55 (private home concerts) and $32 (Neighborhood Church and UCLA Faculty Center series). Tickets are available for purchase through Pacific Serenades by calling (213) 534-3434. Student rush tickets are available for $5 (at the door only) for concert programs held at the Neighborhood Church in Pasadena and the UCLA Faculty Center. For more information, or to request a brochure, please call (213) 534-3434 or visit www.pacser.org.</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/press/22nd-season-features-4-world-premieres/">22nd Season Features 4 World Premieres</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
