<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>News Archive - Pacific Serenades</title>
	<atom:link href="http://pacser.org/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://pacser.org/news/</link>
	<description>New chamber music from the west coast</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 20:01:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Festival of LA Song</title>
		<link>http://pacser.org/news/festival-of-la-song/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Carlson, Artistic Director]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 03:28:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pacser.org/?post_type=news&#038;p=5369</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Pacific Serenades is planning and promoting a Los Angeles County-wide Festival of LA Song, to take place throughout the 2018-19 ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/news/festival-of-la-song/">Festival of LA Song</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pacific Serenades is planning and promoting a Los Angeles County-wide Festival of LA Song, to take place throughout the 2018-19 concert season.</p>
<p>Our idea for this Festival is to celebrate Song in its many manifestations, as created here in the LA area, by having as many ensembles, schools, presenters, etc., include songs by Los Angeles-area composers on their own concerts. This will be a way for organizations to showcase themselves with a shared context between all the participants, in ways that are true to the mission and aesthetic identity of each individual participant. There are lots of ways this could happen, but we happen to think that celebrating songs from this area is a particularly wonderful way to do it.</p>
<p>We’re modeling this on the LA Opera’s Britten 100/LA, a festival held throughout the year 2013. The Opera invited a host of organizations to be involved by programming music by Britten during their regular concerts, but other than spearheading the festival, the Opera had no other direct involvement with the individual organizations’ concerts. It was a remarkable year of many performances of Britten’s music here.</p>
<p>There was a much earlier model, in 1987, called New Music LA, in which organizations throughout the area programmed new music by living composers in a two-week festival. It, too, was wonderful, and it’s time to do something like that again!</p>
<p>This will be a decentralized Festival, but one which will provide the potential for ensembles and organizations—representing remarkably diverse aesthetics and missions—to relate to each other through the common lens of LA Song.</p>
<p>Each organization will commit to programming within their regular season at least one concert that features at least one song by an LA-area composer. The LA composers could be people alive and well, and the programmed songs could be premieres or older pieces. In order to show the depth and breadth of song composition here, we’ll also be happy if songs by composers no longer with us are programmed. Musical style of the songs and of the whole program is entirely up to each organization.</p>
<p>This promises to be an exciting celebration of music, and a fantastic way to showcase the diversity and uniqueness of Song created right here in Los Angeles.</p>
<p><em>This project is supported, in part, by the Los Angeles County Board of Supervisors through the Los Angeles County Arts Commission.</em></p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-5375" src="http://pacser.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/bwlogolacac_no_tag-300x300.jpg" alt="bwlogolacac_no_tag" width="300" height="300" srcset="http://pacser.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/bwlogolacac_no_tag-300x300.jpg 300w, http://pacser.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/bwlogolacac_no_tag-150x150.jpg 150w, http://pacser.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/bwlogolacac_no_tag.jpg 328w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/news/festival-of-la-song/">Festival of LA Song</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Composer Profile: David Goodman</title>
		<link>http://pacser.org/news/composer-profile-david-goodman/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Carlson, Artistic Director]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 05:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Composer Profile]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pacser.org/?post_type=news&#038;p=5189</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>by Mark Carlson In 1999, we commissioned and premiered our first piece by David Goodman, his Piano Quartet, a piece ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/news/composer-profile-david-goodman/">Composer Profile: David Goodman</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>by Mark Carlson</p>
<p>In 1999, we commissioned and premiered our first piece by David Goodman, his Piano Quartet, a piece which our audience clearly loved. I swear that they were dancing down the aisles as they left the concert. I started our conversation by asking David how things were different with him as a composer than they were 17 years ago. </p>
<p>“I think I’m more comfortable with writing what I want to write now.” Part of that he credits to his 19-year tenure as a professor of music theory and composition at Santa Monica College, a position he sees as allowing him to be an outsider to the larger new music scene. At SMC, he is free to follow whatever aesthetic path he chooses without the pressures many composers at big four-year schools feel in producing music that will be accepted within the confines of that world.</p>
<p>One recent work of his is a large-scale piece for chorus and orchestra, Prayers for the Planet, which was the result of his second Ilona Katz Chair of Excellence from the Santa Monica College Foundation. Ilona Katz was a patron of SMC, and her award became a commission to write Prayers for the Planet, which has as its central theme the issue of global and human responsibility. The piece received its world premiere in June of 2011 by the SMC Concert Chorale and the Los Angeles Concert Orchestra under the direction of Dr. James Smith.</p>
<p>Since teaching is clearly very important to him, I asked him about the relationship of his teaching to his composing, and he said the following:</p>
<p>“I think that teaching is an honorable profession, one which gives us more inspiration than if we were just artisan composers. Facing a class twice a week and having to inspire them is invigorating to me, and it positively impacts my music. In the classroom, I teach the music that I really like—lots of early 20th century music, for example—and this reinforces my habits. </p>
<p>“Teaching is really significant, also, because it shows you how much you are connected to people, people we watch go through their training for two years in school, and then beyond. Composing is also about making connections with people. Seeing the whole process of writing a piece from beginning to end is very fulfilling, and the connection it creates with other people is so important to me. I’m never writing music that panders to any audience, but I believe that music should be visceral, tangible, and connective.”</p>
<p>About Walking Music, David said, “This was a great opportunity to rekindle my composing after a few years’ hiatus.  It’s always a plus to have an extra-musical inspiration, and Mary Bomba’s request that the piece relate to her husband Tom’s love of walking was a very fun subject.</p>
<p>“I’m very happy with what I have written, and I hope the players will enjoy playing it.  I’ve had so much fun writing this piece, and I’m just thrilled to be involved in this concert. Your commission to write Walking Music was a real catalyst for me. A new senior-mid-life crisis is averted!”</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/news/composer-profile-david-goodman/">Composer Profile: David Goodman</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Story of a Commission</title>
		<link>http://pacser.org/news/the-story-of-a-commission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tony Spano, Jr.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 05:40:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Commission Interview]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pacser.org/?post_type=news&#038;p=5187</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>by Tony Spano, Jr. Mary Bomba and I first met when she joined the Culver City Adult School Community Band ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/news/the-story-of-a-commission/">The Story of a Commission</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>by Tony Spano, Jr. </p>
<p>Mary Bomba and I first met when she joined the Culver City Adult School Community Band I was conducting as part of my work at Culver City High School. She was our lead trumpet player, working as a hospital chaplain during the day, and making music with the Community Band once a week. </p>
<p>“I first learned of Pacific Serenades from board member Michael Shilub,” Mary explained to me.  “He spoke highly of Pacific Serenades, and it turned out to be the same chamber series that you kept bringing us flyers for at the Culver City Adult School Band.” </p>
<p>“By the time the Adult School Band ended and I moved to the Santa Monica Emeritus College Band, Tom and I had become subscribers,” Mary went on to explain.  “And you and I stayed connected not just because of Pacific Serenades but because my trumpet teacher, Paul Witt, is your colleague [a trumpet player and music teacher at Culver City Middle School].”</p>
<p>Mary and her husband Tom O’Connor have continued to be subscribers to Pacific Serenades concerts. Several years ago, Mary began asking about the process of commissioning a new piece. She began the long plan of honoring her husband’s 70th birthday with a surprise commission. </p>
<p>I asked Mary about keeping the secret for so long.  “It hasn’t been hard to keep the secret,” she responded.  “I just didn’t tell anyone.  But then in March Tom’s siblings started talking about flying him back to Cleveland for his birthday, so I had to fill them in.  And then this month I started letting the rest of the family and our friends know so they could save the date.”</p>
<p>“But what about the surprise for Tom,” I asked. </p>
<p>“As for Tom,” Mary answered, “I think I’ll wait for the postcard to arrive, put a bow on it, and place it on his chair.”</p>
<p>As for the title of the work, Walking Music, Mary suggested the subject of walking as a nod to Tom’s favorite pastime. “Tom loves to walk.  He walks for the pure pleasure of seeing what he can see.  He’s a flaneur,” Mary explained. </p>
<p>While Tom worked in finance for the aerospace industry, Mary’s first career before becoming a hospital chaplain was in the film business.  “I read scripts, and both my parents were in the film business.  My brother still is.  That was probably my first exposure to music, through film, and I remember my father, a motion picture sound editor, telling me how important music was to the movies.  He took me to a presentation on film scoring at the Academy and I remember being fascinated by the click track,” Mary shared. </p>
<p>Mary also explained how she and Tom came to choose our home concerts. “Tom also loves the movies, especially film noir, and he cares a lot about architecture and design. He’s a docent at the Petersen Automotive Museum, Hollyhock House, and the Virginia Robinson Gardens. Tom’s interest in architecture is what prompted us to choose the private home venue for our Pacific Serenades subscription.  We’ve seen some beautiful homes—and afterwards there’s always good food!”</p>
<p>While considering something special for her husband’s 70th birthday, Mary was inspired by our concerts and mission.  “I don’t know that it would ever occur to me to commission a piece of music if it hadn’t been for Pacific Serenades and their emphasis on new works.  But hearing new compositions season after season, and watching fellow subscriber Ursula Krummel regularly commission new pieces, got me thinking about commissioning a piece for Tom.  Both of us are at an age where we don’t need any more stuff.  But to be able to encourage a living, Los Angeles-based composer, to help send a new piece of music into the world, how great is that?”</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/news/the-story-of-a-commission/">The Story of a Commission</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pacific Serenades Welcomes Back Two Young Artists</title>
		<link>http://pacser.org/news/pacific-serenades-welcomes-back-two-young-artists/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 22:38:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artist Profile]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pacser.org/?post_type=news&#038;p=5185</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Pacific Serenades welcomes back young artists Ambroise Aubrun and Ben Bartelt, who performed with us for the first time in ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/news/pacific-serenades-welcomes-back-two-young-artists/">Pacific Serenades Welcomes Back Two Young Artists</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pacific Serenades welcomes back young artists Ambroise Aubrun and Ben Bartelt, who performed with us for the first time in 2014 and 2015, respectively.</p>
<p>Asked how they would describe the appeal of playing chamber music, and how chamber music figures in their lives, as well as what made them look forward to playing this Pacific Serenades concert, they answered:</p>
<p>“My passion for chamber music started simply because chamber music was always the really fun class to go to when I was growing up. It was the moment when I could see my friends and it really gave a sense to those long hours of practicing on my own! Later on, I discovered the endless repertoire of chamber music, and I could never get away from it. I moved to Los Angeles to study with the amazing Guillaume Sutre (former 1st violin of the Ysaÿe Quartet), who is one of the greatest masters of chamber music playing, and he took my passion for chamber music to a completely different level. After UCLA, I was also lucky to study with another fantastic chamber musician, Martin Beaver (former 1st violinist of the Tokyo Quartet). Studying with such fascinating and passionate musicians really helped me become a smarter violinist, and I believe that chamber music is the fundamental of music playing, and that we should approach any pieces of the repertoire, concertos, symphonies as such.</p>
<p>“Pacific Serenades is a wonderful place to go, both as a musician or as part of the audience. Mark is truly passionate about music and offers high quality performances and very interesting programs. He proposes programs that combine world premieres and more known pieces of the repertoire, which is always so interesting for us as musicians, since we get to discover a new composer and a new piece every time. The venues he chooses are very intimate, which really brings the audience closer to the musicians. I first played in Pacific Serenades two years ago, and at that time, we were not sure if Pacific Serenades was going to survive the financial struggles that so many great concert series are facing. Being able to play there again brings me great joy, and I really hope to hear great concerts at Pacific Serenades in many years to come.” —Ambroise Aubrun</p>
<p>“I enjoy the collaborative aspect of playing chamber music. Everything you hear is the result of teamwork: everyone contributes an important role, and has times both in the spotlight and in the background; and interpretational decisions can be made democratically. There is also an incredibly rich and diverse repertoire, of which it seems I&#8217;ve only barely scratched the surface. For these reasons, I like to play chamber music as often as possible!</p>
<p>“It is always a treat to be able to perform with high caliber musicians. This is plenty of reason already to be looking forward to playing this concert. In addition, the program includes a piece which I have been wanting to perform for a long time, the Stravinsky Concertino. I consider it a masterpiece which isn&#8217;t performed as often as it should be, and I can&#8217;t wait to share it with the audience!” —Ben Bartelt</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/news/pacific-serenades-welcomes-back-two-young-artists/">Pacific Serenades Welcomes Back Two Young Artists</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Concert Details</title>
		<link>http://pacser.org/news/concert-details/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Carlson, Artistic Director]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 19:29:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pacser.org/?post_type=news&#038;p=5183</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Smiles of a Summer Day Sunday, June 26 4:00 pm The home of Mark Freund &#038; Trice Koopman in Pacific ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/news/concert-details/">Concert Details</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Smiles of a Summer Day</p>
<p>Sunday, June 26 4:00 pm<br />
The home of Mark Freund &#038; Trice Koopman in Pacific Palisades</p>
<p>Tuesday, June 28, 8:00 pm<br />
The UCLA Faculty Center</p>
<p>Stravinsky: Concertino for string quartet (1920)<br />
Mendelssohn: String Quartet in E flat major, Op. 44, No. 3<br />
David Goodman: Walking Music, for flute and string quartet<br />
	our 113th premiere!</p>
<p>Roger Wilkie, violin<br />
Ambroise Aubrun, violin<br />
Ben Bartelt, viola<br />
David Speltz, cello<br />
Mark Carlson, flute</p>
<p>Program and artists subject to change without notice.<br />
For complete information, visit www.pacser.org.  213-534-3434</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/news/concert-details/">Concert Details</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pacific Serenades still needs your donations!</title>
		<link>http://pacser.org/news/pacific-serenades-still-needs-your-donations-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Carlson, Artistic Director]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 19:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pacser.org/?post_type=news&#038;p=5181</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>To help with our plans going forward, and to help us complete the funding for our upcoming concert, please make ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/news/pacific-serenades-still-needs-your-donations-3/">Pacific Serenades still needs your donations!</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>To help with our plans going forward, and to help us complete the funding for our upcoming concert, please make a tax-deductible gift to Pacific Serenades. We are especially looking for donations to allow us to pay our talented musicians. A donation of $1,000 or above will sponsor one of the five performers.</p>
<p>But ALL donations, small and larger, are welcome—and needed!</p>
<p>Just go to www.pacser.org and click on the “Donate” button. Easy!</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/news/pacific-serenades-still-needs-your-donations-3/">Pacific Serenades still needs your donations!</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Freund-Koopman Residence</title>
		<link>http://pacser.org/news/the-freund-koopman-residence-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Carlson, Artistic Director]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 19:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pacser.org/?post_type=news&#038;p=5179</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The house was built in 1940 on a double lot in a cul-de-sac in Pacific Palisades. Mark Freund and Trice ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/news/the-freund-koopman-residence-2/">The Freund-Koopman Residence</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The house was built in 1940 on a double lot in a cul-de-sac in Pacific Palisades. Mark Freund and Trice Koopman purchased it in 1983 and have done two extensive remodels, completed in 1992 and 2004. Designed by architect Lorcan O&#8217;Herlihy, the first remodel very early in his career, the second after he was well established, both keep a continuity of design and materials. “We tend to refer to it as comfortable modern,” Mark says. O’Herlihy describes the upstairs (the second remodel) as light skin construction, meaning the house is skinned in glass (mostly) while the structural support is more internal.</p>
<p>Our 26th season opened with a string quartet concert in this beautiful house, and the acoustic of the room was stunning. This year, an afternoon concert will allow us to take advantage after the concert of the deck, which is in and of itself visually striking and which also has beautiful views of the surrounding landscapes.</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/news/the-freund-koopman-residence-2/">The Freund-Koopman Residence</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ticket Specials for June 26 &#038; 28 Concerts through June 1</title>
		<link>http://pacser.org/news/ticket-specials-for-june-26-28-concerts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Carlson, Artistic Director]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 19:22:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pacser.org/?post_type=news&#038;p=5174</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ticket Specials Sunday, June 26 4:00 pm The home of Mark Freund &#38; Trice Koopman in Pacific Palisades Seating is ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/news/ticket-specials-for-june-26-28-concerts/">Ticket Specials for June 26 &#038; 28 Concerts through June 1</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Ticket Specials</strong></p>
<p>Sunday, June 26 4:00 pm<br />
The home of Mark Freund &amp; Trice Koopman in Pacific Palisades<br />
Seating is limited; directions will be given upon receipt of payment.<br />
Admission: $59 (refreshments included)<br />
Online discount price: $54 (plus handling fee)<br />
<strong>Early-bird special price: $45 (plus handling fee) if paid for online by June 1, 2016</strong><br />
<strong>Use code Home16 at checkout</strong></p>
<p>Tuesday, June 28, 8:00 pm<br />
The UCLA Faculty Center<br />
405 N. Hilgard Ave. (at Westholme)<br />
For dinner reservations at the UCLA Faculty Center, call (310) 825-0877<br />
Admission: $34 or $5 for full-time students with ID<br />
Online discount price: $28 (plus handling fee)<br />
<strong>Early-bird special price: $26 (plus handling fee) if paid for online by June 1, 2016</strong><br />
<strong>Use code UCLA16 at checkout</strong></p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/news/ticket-specials-for-june-26-28-concerts/">Ticket Specials for June 26 &#038; 28 Concerts through June 1</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Welcome to the New Pacific Serenades Website!</title>
		<link>http://pacser.org/news/welcome-to-the-new-pacific-serenades-website/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Meredith Marschak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 16:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pacser.org/?post_type=news&#038;p=4983</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>To reflect Pacific Serenades’ mission of generating and promoting new music by Southern California composers, we have redesigned and relaunched ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/news/welcome-to-the-new-pacific-serenades-website/">Welcome to the New Pacific Serenades Website!</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>To reflect Pacific Serenades’ mission of generating and promoting new music by Southern California composers, we have redesigned and relaunched our website.  With an eye to retaining the rich archival nature of our former site, we have developed a contemporary version that complements our goal of championing our published works and the incredible achievements of our composers.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>We have long taken pride in how many performances by other ensembles our 112 commissioned works have received—some as many as 100 performances, and counting!—and nothing would make us happier than to continue getting those pieces out into the world. We see our new website as an important tool in making that happen.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>And while we are deeply committed to—and will never abandon—our Southern California roots, we know that not everyone is able to attend one of our concerts, or to hear our music live. Thus, this site isn’t just a way to promote our concerts; it is a platform through which we can broaden the reach of our music through our professional CDs, performance recordings, and performances by other ensembles—all ways of broadcasting the uniqueness of Southern California music to the rest of the world.</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/news/welcome-to-the-new-pacific-serenades-website/">Welcome to the New Pacific Serenades Website!</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pacific Serenades Commissions Yalil Guerra for the 2016 HEAR NOW Festival</title>
		<link>http://pacser.org/news/pacific-serenades-commissions-yalil-guerra-for-the-2016-hear-now-festival/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Meredith Marschak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 16:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pacser.org/?post_type=news&#038;p=4995</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Pacific Serenades has commissioned Latin Grammy Award-winning composer Yalil Guerra to write a new piece for the 2016 HEAR NOW ...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/news/pacific-serenades-commissions-yalil-guerra-for-the-2016-hear-now-festival/">Pacific Serenades Commissions Yalil Guerra for the 2016 HEAR NOW Festival</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pacific Serenades has commissioned Latin Grammy Award-winning composer Yalil Guerra to write a new piece for the 2016 HEAR NOW Festival of New Music by Contemporary Los Angeles Composers.  This commission was made possible by the generous support of our long-time board member, Ursula Krummel.  The world premiere of composer Guerra’s piece will be on Sunday, April 24th, 2016 at First Lutheran Church in Venice, CA.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>As our Artistic Director Mark Carlson notes, “I always wanted Pacific Serenades to commission new works by Southern California composers for other ensembles, festivals, or presenters.  After 27 concert seasons and 111 new chamber works commissioned and premiered by us, by 63 different composers, we now have the opportunity to experiment with commissioning a work for another organization.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>“Our first foray into this territory is commissioning a work for the HEAR NOW Music Festival, with whom we share a strong core value: a passionate commitment to supporting composers of Southern California.  Our mutual choice for this commission is Yalil Guerra.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Composer Guerra notes, “I am thrilled and honored for receiving this commission.  This sets a new step in my composing career, and I am truly excited about it.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>HEAR NOW is dedicated to providing an ever-broadening spotlight on the musical imagination of composers based in the Los Angeles area.  The results from the last five festivals are 90 new and recent works by 80 individual Los Angeles-based composers, both well known and less-well known.  The Festival will take place from April 21-24, and will also feature collaborations with the LA Chamber Orchestra, UCLA Philharmonia, and People Inside Electronics.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>For more information, please visit: <a href="http://www.hearnowmusicfestival.com/">http://www.hearnowmusicfestival.com</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://pacser.org/news/pacific-serenades-commissions-yalil-guerra-for-the-2016-hear-now-festival/">Pacific Serenades Commissions Yalil Guerra for the 2016 HEAR NOW Festival</a> appeared first on <a href="http://pacser.org">Pacific Serenades</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
